<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?> 
<Language name="English" id="9" identifier="en" iso639="en" iso3166="us">
  <Species>
    <!-- "^"(\d*)"\t"(\d*)"\t"([\w\S.\- ]*)"\t"([\w ’,-]*)"\t"(\d*)"\t"(\d*)"\t"(\d*)"\t"([\w\s\d.’,\-—“”!/():♀♂]*|[\r])"" | <Pokemon id="$1" language="$2" name="$3" genus="$4">$8</Pokemon> -->
<Pokemon id="0" language="9" name="TestPokemon" genus="Test" form0="test0" form1="test1" form2="test2" form3="test3">This is a test.
This is unimportant text and values,
to be used for testing the PokemonData class.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="1" language="9" name="Bulbasaur" genus="Seed">Bulbasaur can be seen napping in bright sunlight.
There is a seed on its back. By soaking up the sun’s rays,
the seed grows progressively larger.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="2" language="9" name="Ivysaur" genus="Seed">There is a bud on this Pokémon’s back. To support its weight,
Ivysaur’s legs and trunk grow thick and strong.
If it starts spending more time lying in the sunlight,
it’s a sign that the bud will bloom into a large flower soon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="3" language="9" name="Venusaur" genus="Seed">There is a large flower on Venusaur’s back. The flower is said
to take on vivid colors if it gets plenty of nutrition and sunlight.
The flower’s aroma soothes the emotions of people.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="4" language="9" name="Charmander" genus="Lizard">The flame that burns at the tip of its tail is an indication
of its emotions. The flame wavers when Charmander
is enjoying itself. If the Pokémon becomes enraged,
the flame burns fiercely.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="5" language="9" name="Charmeleon" genus="Flame">Charmeleon mercilessly destroys its foes using its sharp
claws. If it encounters a strong foe, it turns aggressive.
In this excited state, the flame at the tip of its tail flares with
a bluish white color.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="6" language="9" name="Charizard" genus="Flame">Charizard flies around the sky in search of powerful opponents.
It breathes fire of such great heat that it melts anything.
However, it never turns its fiery breath on any opponent
weaker than itself.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="7" language="9" name="Squirtle" genus="Tiny Turtle">Squirtle’s shell is not merely used for protection.
The shell’s rounded shape and the grooves on its
surface help minimize resistance in water,
enabling this Pokémon to swim at high speeds.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="8" language="9" name="Wartortle" genus="Turtle">Its tail is large and covered with a rich, thick fur. The tail
becomes increasingly deeper in color as Wartortle ages.
The scratches on its shell are evidence of this Pokémon’s
toughness as a battler.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="9" language="9" name="Blastoise" genus="Shellfish">Blastoise has water spouts that protrude from its shell.
The water spouts are very accurate.
They can shoot bullets of water with enough accuracy
to strike empty cans from a distance of over 160 feet.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="10" language="9" name="Caterpie" genus="Worm">Caterpie has a voracious appetite. It can devour leaves
bigger than its body right before your eyes. From its antenna,
this Pokémon releases a terrifically strong odor.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="11" language="9" name="Metapod" genus="Cocoon">The shell covering this Pokémon’s body is as hard as an
iron slab. Metapod does not move very much.
It stays still because it is preparing its soft innards for
evolution inside the hard shell.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="12" language="9" name="Butterfree" genus="Butterfly">Butterfree has a superior ability to search for delicious honey
from flowers. It can even search out, extract, and carry honey
from flowers that are blooming over six miles from its nest.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="13" language="9" name="Weedle" genus="Hairy Bug">Weedle has an extremely acute sense of smell. It is capable
of distinguishing its favorite kinds of leaves from those it
dislikes just by sniffing with its big red proboscis (nose).</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="14" language="9" name="Kakuna" genus="Cocoon">Kakuna remains virtually immobile as it clings to a tree.
However, on the inside, it is extremely busy as it prepares
for its coming evolution.
This is evident from how hot the shell becomes to the touch.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="15" language="9" name="Beedrill" genus="Poison Bee">Beedrill is extremely territorial. No one should ever approach
its nest—this is for their own safety. If angered, they will attack
in a furious swarm.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="16" language="9" name="Pidgey" genus="Tiny Bird">Pidgey has an extremely sharp sense of direction.
It is capable of unerringly returning home to its nest,
however far it may be removed from its familiar surroundings.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="17" language="9" name="Pidgeotto" genus="Bird">Pidgeotto claims a large area as its own territory. This
Pokémon flies around, patrolling its living space. If its territory
is violated, it shows no mercy in thoroughly punishing the foe
with its sharp claws.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="18" language="9" name="Pidgeot" genus="Bird">This Pokémon has a dazzling plumage of beautifully
glossy feathers. Many Trainers are captivated by the
striking beauty of the feathers on its head, compelling
them to choose Pidgeot as their Pokémon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="19" language="9" name="Rattata" genus="Mouse">Rattata is cautious in the extreme. Even while it is asleep,
it constantly listens by moving its ears around. It is not
picky about where it lives—it will make its nest anywhere.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="20" language="9" name="Raticate" genus="Mouse">Raticate’s sturdy fangs grow steadily. To keep them
ground down, it gnaws on rocks and logs. It may
even chew on the walls of houses.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="21" language="9" name="Spearow" genus="Tiny Bird">Spearow has a very loud cry that can be heard over
half a mile away. If its high, keening cry is heard echoing all
around, it is a sign that they are warning each other of danger.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="22" language="9" name="Fearow" genus="Beak">Fearow is recognized by its long neck and elongated beak.
They are conveniently shaped for catching prey in soil or
water. It deftly moves its long and skinny beak to pluck prey.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="23" language="9" name="Ekans" genus="Snake">Ekans curls itself up in a spiral while it rests. Assuming this
position allows it to quickly respond to a threat from any
direction with a glare from its upraised head.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="24" language="9" name="Arbok" genus="Cobra">This Pokémon is terrifically strong in order to constrict things
with its body. It can even flatten steel oil drums. Once Arbok
wraps its body around its foe, escaping its crunching embrace
is impossible.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="25" language="9" name="Pikachu" genus="Mouse">This Pokémon has electricity-storing pouches on its cheeks.
These appear to become electrically charged during the night
while Pikachu sleeps. It occasionally discharges electricity
when it is dozy after waking up.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="26" language="9" name="Raichu" genus="Mouse">This Pokémon exudes a weak electrical charge from all over
its body that makes it take on a slight glow in darkness.
Raichu plants its tail in the ground to discharge electricity.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="27" language="9" name="Sandshrew" genus="Mouse">Sandshrew has a very dry hide that is extremely tough.
The Pokémon can roll into a ball that repels any attack.
At night, it burrows into the desert sand to sleep.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="28" language="9" name="Sandslash" genus="Mouse">Sandslash can roll up its body as if it were a ball covered
with large spikes. In battle, this Pokémon will try to make
the foe flinch by jabbing it with its spines. It then leaps at
the stunned foe to tear wildly with its sharp claws.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="29" language="9" name="Nidoran♀" genus="Poison Pin">Nidoran♀ has barbs that secrete a powerful poison.
They are thought to have developed as protection for
this small-bodied Pokémon. When enraged, it releases
a horrible toxin from its horn.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="30" language="9" name="Nidorina" genus="Poison Pin">When Nidorina are with their friends or family, they keep
their barbs tucked away to prevent hurting each other.
This Pokémon appears to become nervous if separated
from the others.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="31" language="9" name="Nidoqueen" genus="Drill">Nidoqueen’s body is encased in extremely hard scales.
It is adept at sending foes flying with harsh tackles. This
Pokémon is at its strongest when it is defending its young.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="32" language="9" name="Nidoran♂" genus="Poison Pin">Nidoran♂ has developed muscles for moving its ears. Thanks
to them, the ears can be freely moved in any direction. Even
the slightest sound does not escape this Pokémon’s notice.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="33" language="9" name="Nidorino" genus="Poison Pin">Nidorino has a horn that is harder than a diamond. If it senses
a hostile presence, all the barbs on its back bristle up at once,
and it challenges the foe with all its might.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="34" language="9" name="Nidoking" genus="Drill">Nidoking’s thick tail packs enormously destructive power.
With one swing, it can topple a metal transmission tower. Once
this Pokémon goes on a rampage, there is no stopping it.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="35" language="9" name="Clefairy" genus="Fairy">On every night of a full moon, groups of this Pokémon
come out to play. When dawn arrives, the tired Clefairy
return to their quiet mountain retreats and go to sleep
nestled up against each other.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="36" language="9" name="Clefable" genus="Fairy">Clefable moves by skipping lightly as if it were flying using
its wings. Its bouncy step lets it even walk on water.
It is known to take strolls on lakes on quiet, moonlit nights.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="37" language="9" name="Vulpix" genus="Fox">Inside Vulpix’s body burns a flame that never goes out.
During the daytime, when the temperatures rise, this
Pokémon releases flames from its mouth to prevent its
body from growing too hot.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="38" language="9" name="Ninetales" genus="Fox">Legend has it that Ninetales came into being when
nine wizards possessing sacred powers merged into one.
This Pokémon is highly intelligent—it can understand
human speech.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="39" language="9" name="Jigglypuff" genus="Balloon">When this Pokémon sings, it never pauses to breathe.
If it is in a battle against an opponent that does not easily
fall asleep, Jigglypuff cannot breathe, endangering its life.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="40" language="9" name="Wigglytuff" genus="Balloon">Wigglytuff’s body is very flexible. By inhaling deeply,
this Pokémon can inflate itself seemingly without end.
Once inflated, Wigglytuff bounces along lightly like a balloon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="41" language="9" name="Zubat" genus="Bat">Zubat avoids sunlight because exposure causes it to become
unhealthy. During the daytime, it stays in caves or under
the eaves of old houses, sleeping while hanging upside down.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="42" language="9" name="Golbat" genus="Bat">Golbat bites down on prey with its four fangs and drinks
the victim’s blood. It becomes active on inky dark
moonless nights, flying around to attack people and Pokémon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="43" language="9" name="Oddish" genus="Weed">Oddish searches for fertile, nutrient-rich soil, then plants itself.
During the daytime, while it is planted, this Pokémon’s feet
are thought to change shape and become similar to the roots
of trees.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="44" language="9" name="Gloom" genus="Weed">From its mouth Gloom drips honey that smells absolutely
horrible. Apparently, it loves the horrid stench. It sniffs the
noxious fumes and then drools even more of its honey.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="45" language="9" name="Vileplume" genus="Flower">Vileplume has the world’s largest petals. They are used to
attract prey that are then doused with toxic spores. Once the
prey are immobilized, this Pokémon catches and devours them.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="46" language="9" name="Paras" genus="Mushroom">Paras has parasitic mushrooms growing on its back called
tochukaso. They grow large by drawing nutrients from this
Bug Pokémon host. They are highly valued as a medicine
for extending life.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="47" language="9" name="Parasect" genus="Mushroom">Parasect is known to infest large trees en masse and drain
nutrients from the lower trunk and roots. When an infested
tree dies, they move onto another tree all at once.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="48" language="9" name="Venonat" genus="Insect">Venonat is said to have evolved with a coat of thin, stiff hair
that covers its entire body for protection. It possesses large
eyes that never fail to spot even minuscule prey.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="49" language="9" name="Venomoth" genus="Poison Moth">Venomoth is nocturnal—it is a Pokémon that only becomes
active at night. Its favorite prey are small insects that gather
around streetlights, attracted by the light in the darkness.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="50" language="9" name="Diglett" genus="Mole">Diglett are raised in most farms. The reason is simple—
wherever this Pokémon burrows, the soil is left perfectly tilled
for planting crops. This soil is made ideal for growing
delicious vegetables.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="51" language="9" name="Dugtrio" genus="Mole">Dugtrio are actually triplets that emerged from one body.
As a result, each triplet thinks exactly like the other two
triplets. They work cooperatively to burrow endlessly.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="52" language="9" name="Meowth" genus="Scratch Cat">Meowth withdraws its sharp claws into its paws to slinkily sneak
about without making any incriminating footsteps. For some
reason, this Pokémon loves shiny coins that glitter with light.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="53" language="9" name="Persian" genus="Classy Cat">Persian has six bold whiskers that give it a look of toughness.
The whiskers sense air movements to determine what is in the
Pokémon’s surrounding vicinity. It becomes docile if grabbed
by the whiskers.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="54" language="9" name="Psyduck" genus="Duck">If it uses its mysterious power, Psyduck can’t remember
having done so. It apparently can’t form a memory of such
an event because it goes into an altered state that is much
like deep sleep.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="55" language="9" name="Golduck" genus="Duck">Golduck is the fastest swimmer among all Pokémon. It swims
effortlessly, even in a rough, stormy sea. It sometimes rescues
people from wrecked ships floundering in high seas.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="56" language="9" name="Mankey" genus="Pig Monkey">When Mankey starts shaking and its nasal breathing turns
rough, it’s a sure sign that it is becoming angry. However,
because it goes into a towering rage almost instantly,
it is impossible for anyone to flee its wrath.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="57" language="9" name="Primeape" genus="Pig Monkey">When Primeape becomes furious, its blood circulation
is boosted. In turn, its muscles are made even stronger.
However, it also becomes much less intelligent at the
same time.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="58" language="9" name="Growlithe" genus="Puppy">Growlithe has a superb sense of smell. Once it smells anything,
this Pokémon won’t forget the scent, no matter what. It uses
its advanced olfactory sense to determine the emotions of
other living things.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="59" language="9" name="Arcanine" genus="Legendary">Arcanine is known for its high speed. It is said to be capable
of running over 6,200 miles in a single day and night. The
fire that blazes wildly within this Pokémon’s body is its source
of power.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="60" language="9" name="Poliwag" genus="Tadpole">Poliwag has a very thin skin. It is possible to see the
Pokémon’s spiral innards right through the skin. Despite its
thinness, however, the skin is also very flexible. Even sharp
fangs bounce right off it.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="61" language="9" name="Poliwhirl" genus="Tadpole">The surface of Poliwhirl’s body is always wet and slick with
a slimy fluid. Because of this slippery covering, it can easily
slip and slide out of the clutches of any enemy in battle.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="62" language="9" name="Poliwrath" genus="Tadpole">Poliwrath’s highly developed, brawny muscles never grow
fatigued, however much it exercises. It is so tirelessly strong,
this Pokémon can swim back and forth across the ocean
without effort.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="63" language="9" name="Abra" genus="Psi">Abra needs to sleep for eighteen hours a day. If it doesn’t,
this Pokémon loses its ability to use telekinetic powers. If it is
attacked, Abra escapes using Teleport while it is still sleeping.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="64" language="9" name="Kadabra" genus="Psi">Kadabra holds a silver spoon in its hand. The spoon is used
to amplify the alpha waves in its brain. Without the spoon, the
Pokémon is said to be limited to half the usual amount of its
telekinetic powers.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="65" language="9" name="Alakazam" genus="Psi">Alakazam’s brain continually grows, infinitely multiplying
brain cells. This amazing brain gives this Pokémon an
astoundingly high IQ of 5,000. It has a thorough memory
of everything that has occurred in the world.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="66" language="9" name="Machop" genus="Superpower">Machop exercises by hefting around a Graveler as if it were
a barbell. There are some Machop that travel the world in a
quest to master all kinds of martial arts.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="67" language="9" name="Machoke" genus="Superpower">Machoke undertakes bodybuilding every day even as
it helps people with tough, physically demanding labor.
On its days off, this Pokémon heads to the fields and
mountains to exercise and train.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="68" language="9" name="Machamp" genus="Superpower">Machamp is known as the Pokémon that has mastered
every kind of martial arts. If it grabs hold of the foe with its
four arms, the battle is all but over. The hapless foe is thrown
far over the horizon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="69" language="9" name="Bellsprout" genus="Flower">Bellsprout’s thin and flexible body lets it bend and sway
to avoid any attack, however strong it may be. From its mouth,
this Pokémon spits a corrosive fluid that melts even iron.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="70" language="9" name="Weepinbell" genus="Flycatcher">Weepinbell has a large hook on its rear end. At night, the
Pokémon hooks on to a tree branch and goes to sleep.
If it moves around in its sleep, it may wake up to find itself
on the ground.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="71" language="9" name="Victreebel" genus="Flycatcher">Victreebel has a long vine that extends from its head.
This vine is waved and flicked about as if it were an animal
to attract prey. When an unsuspecting prey draws near,
this Pokémon swallows it whole.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="72" language="9" name="Tentacool" genus="Jellyfish">Tentacool absorbs sunlight and refracts it using water inside
its body to convert it into beam energy. This Pokémon shoots
beams from the small round organ above its eyes.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="73" language="9" name="Tentacruel" genus="Jellyfish">Tentacruel has tentacles that can be freely elongated
and shortened at will. It ensnares prey with its tentacles
and weakens the prey by dosing it with a harsh toxin.
It can catch up to 80 prey at the same time.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="74" language="9" name="Geodude" genus="Rock">When Geodude sleeps deeply, it buries itself halfway into the
ground. It will not awaken even if hikers step on it unwittingly.
In the morning, this Pokémon rolls downhill in search of food.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="75" language="9" name="Graveler" genus="Rock">Rocks are Graveler’s favorite food. This Pokémon will climb a
mountain from the base to the summit, crunchingly feasting on
rocks all the while. Upon reaching the peak, it rolls back down
to the bottom.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="76" language="9" name="Golem" genus="Megaton">Golem is known for rolling down from mountains. To prevent
them from rolling into the homes of people downhill, grooves
have been dug into the sides of mountains to serve as
guideways for diverting this Pokémon’s course.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="77" language="9" name="Ponyta" genus="Fire Horse">Ponyta is very weak at birth. It can barely stand up.
This Pokémon becomes stronger by stumbling and
falling to keep up with its parent.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="78" language="9" name="Rapidash" genus="Fire Horse">Rapidash usually can be seen casually cantering in the fields
and plains. However, when this Pokémon turns serious, its
fiery manes flare and blaze as it gallops its way up to 150 mph.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="79" language="9" name="Slowpoke" genus="Dopey">Slowpoke uses its tail to catch prey by dipping it in water
at the side of a river. However, this Pokémon often forgets
what it’s doing and often spends entire days just loafing
at water’s edge.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="80" language="9" name="Slowbro" genus="Hermit Crab">Slowbro’s tail has a Shellder firmly attached with a bite.
As a result, the tail can’t be used for fishing anymore. This
causes Slowbro to grudgingly swim and catch prey instead.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="81" language="9" name="Magnemite" genus="Magnet">Magnemite floats in the air by emitting electromagnetic waves
from the units at its sides. These waves block gravity. This
Pokémon becomes incapable of flight if its internal electrical
supply is depleted.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="82" language="9" name="Magneton" genus="Magnet">Magneton emits a powerful magnetic force that is fatal to
electronics and precision instruments. Because of this, it is
said that some towns warn people to keep this Pokémon
inside a Poké Ball.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="83" language="9" name="Farfetch’d" genus="Wild Duck">Farfetch’d is always seen with a stalk from a plant of some
sort. Apparently, there are good stalks and bad stalks. This
Pokémon has been known to fight with others over stalks.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="84" language="9" name="Doduo" genus="Twin Bird">Doduo’s two heads contain completely identical brains. A
scientific study reported that on rare occasions, there will be
examples of this Pokémon possessing different sets of brains.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="85" language="9" name="Dodrio" genus="Triple Bird">Apparently, the heads aren’t the only parts of the body that
Dodrio has three of. It has three sets of hearts and lungs as
well, so it is capable of running long distances without rest.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="86" language="9" name="Seel" genus="Sea Lion">Seel hunts for prey in the frigid sea underneath sheets of ice.
When it needs to breathe, it punches a hole through the ice
with the sharply protruding section of its head.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="87" language="9" name="Dewgong" genus="Sea Lion">Dewgong loves to snooze on bitterly cold ice. The sight of
this Pokémon sleeping on a glacier was mistakenly thought
to be a mermaid by a mariner long ago.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="88" language="9" name="Grimer" genus="Sludge">Grimer emerged from the sludge that settled on a polluted
seabed. This Pokémon loves anything filthy. It constantly
leaks a horribly germ-infested fluid from all over its body.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="89" language="9" name="Muk" genus="Sludge">This Pokémon’s favorite food is anything that is repugnantly
filthy. In dirty towns where people think nothing of throwing
away litter on the streets, Muk are certain to gather.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="90" language="9" name="Shellder" genus="Bivalve">At night, this Pokémon uses its broad tongue to burrow a hole
in the seafloor sand and then sleep in it. While it is sleeping,
Shellder closes its shell, but leaves its tongue hanging out.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="91" language="9" name="Cloyster" genus="Bivalve">Cloyster is capable of swimming in the sea. It does so by
swallowing water, then jetting it out toward the rear. This
Pokémon shoots spikes from its shell using the same system.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="92" language="9" name="Gastly" genus="Gas">Gastly is largely composed of gaseous matter. When exposed
to a strong wind, the gaseous body quickly dwindles away.
Groups of this Pokémon cluster under the eaves of houses to
escape the ravages of wind.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="93" language="9" name="Haunter" genus="Gas">Haunter is a dangerous Pokémon. If one beckons you while
floating in darkness, you must never approach it. This Pokémon
will try to lick you with its tongue and steal your life away.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="94" language="9" name="Gengar" genus="Shadow">Sometimes, on a dark night, your shadow thrown by a
streetlight will suddenly and startlingly overtake you.
It is actually a Gengar running past you, pretending to be
your shadow.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="95" language="9" name="Onix" genus="Rock Snake">Onix has a magnet in its brain. It acts as a compass so that
this Pokémon does not lose direction while it is tunneling.
As it grows older, its body becomes increasingly rounder
and smoother.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="96" language="9" name="Drowzee" genus="Hypnosis">If your nose becomes itchy while you are sleeping, it’s a sure
sign that one of these Pokémon is standing above your pillow
and trying to eat your dream through your nostrils.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="97" language="9" name="Hypno" genus="Hypnosis">Hypno holds a pendulum in its hand. The arcing movement and
glitter of the pendulum lull the foe into a deep state of
hypnosis. While this Pokémon searches for prey, it polishes
the pendulum.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="98" language="9" name="Krabby" genus="River Crab">Krabby live on beaches, burrowed inside holes dug into
the sand. On sandy beaches with little in the way of food,
these Pokémon can be seen squabbling with each other
over territory.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="99" language="9" name="Kingler" genus="Pincer">Kingler has an enormous, oversized claw. It waves this huge
claw in the air to communicate with others. However, because
the claw is so heavy, the Pokémon quickly tires.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="100" language="9" name="Voltorb" genus="Ball">Voltorb is extremely sensitive—it explodes at the slightest
of shocks. It is rumored that it was first created when a
Poké Ball was exposed to a powerful pulse of energy.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="101" language="9" name="Electrode" genus="Ball">One of Electrode’s characteristics is its attraction to electricity.
It is a problematical Pokémon that congregates mostly at
electrical power plants to feed on electricity that has just
been generated.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="102" language="9" name="Exeggcute" genus="Egg">This Pokémon consists of six eggs that form a closely knit
cluster. The six eggs attract each other and spin around.
When cracks increasingly appear on the eggs, Exeggcute is
close to evolution.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="103" language="9" name="Exeggutor" genus="Coconut">Exeggutor originally came from the tropics. Its heads
steadily grow larger from exposure to strong sunlight. It is
said that when the heads fall off, they group together to
form Exeggcute.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="104" language="9" name="Cubone" genus="Lonely">Cubone pines for the mother it will never see again. Seeing a
likeness of its mother in the full moon, it cries. The stains on
the skull the Pokémon wears are made by the tears it sheds.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="105" language="9" name="Marowak" genus="Bone Keeper">Marowak is the evolved form of a Cubone that has overcome
its sadness at the loss of its mother and grown tough. This
Pokémon’s tempered and hardened spirit is not easily broken.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="106" language="9" name="Hitmonlee" genus="Kicking">Hitmonlee’s legs freely contract and stretch. Using these
springlike legs, it bowls over foes with devastating kicks.
After battle, it rubs down its legs and loosens the muscles
to overcome fatigue.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="107" language="9" name="Hitmonchan" genus="Punching">Hitmonchan is said to possess the spirit of a boxer who had
been working toward a world championship. This Pokémon
has an indomitable spirit and will never give up in the face
of adversity.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="108" language="9" name="Lickitung" genus="Licking">Whenever Lickitung comes across something new, it will
unfailingly give it a lick. It does so because it memorizes things
by texture and by taste. It is somewhat put off by sour things.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="109" language="9" name="Koffing" genus="Poison Gas">Koffing embodies toxic substances. It mixes the toxins with raw
garbage to set off a chemical reaction that results in a terribly
powerful poison gas. The higher the temperature, the more gas
is concocted by this Pokémon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="110" language="9" name="Weezing" genus="Poison Gas">Weezing alternately shrinks and inflates its twin bodies to mix
together toxic gases inside. The more the gases are mixed,
the more powerful the toxins become. The Pokémon also
becomes more putrid.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="111" language="9" name="Rhyhorn" genus="Spikes">Rhyhorn’s brain is very small. It is so dense, while on a run
it forgets why it started running in the first place. It apparently
remembers sometimes if it demolishes something.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="112" language="9" name="Rhydon" genus="Drill">Rhydon has a horn that serves as a drill. It is used for
destroying rocks and boulders. This Pokémon occasionally
rams into streams of magma, but the armor-like hide prevents
it from feeling the heat.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="113" language="9" name="Chansey" genus="Egg">Chansey lays nutritionally excellent eggs on an everyday basis.
The eggs are so delicious, they are easily and eagerly
devoured by even those people who have lost their appetite.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="114" language="9" name="Tangela" genus="Vine">Tangela’s vines snap off easily if they are grabbed. This
happens without pain, allowing it to make a quick getaway.
The lost vines are replaced by newly grown vines the very
next day.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="115" language="9" name="Kangaskhan" genus="Parent">If you come across a young Kangaskhan playing by itself,
you must never disturb it or attempt to catch it. The baby
Pokémon’s parent is sure to be in the area, and it will
become violently enraged at you.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="116" language="9" name="Horsea" genus="Dragon">If Horsea senses danger, it will reflexively spray a dense
black ink from its mouth and try to escape. This Pokémon
swims by cleverly flapping the fin on its back.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="117" language="9" name="Seadra" genus="Dragon">Seadra generates whirlpools by spinning its body.
The whirlpools are strong enough to swallow even
fishing boats. This Pokémon weakens prey with
these currents, then swallows it whole.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="118" language="9" name="Goldeen" genus="Goldfish">Goldeen loves swimming wild and free in rivers and ponds.
If one of these Pokémon is placed in an aquarium, it will
shatter even the thickest glass with one ram of its horn
and make its escape.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="119" language="9" name="Seaking" genus="Goldfish">Seaking is very protective of its eggs. The male and female
will take turns patrolling around their nest and eggs. The
guarding of eggs by these Pokémon goes on for over a month.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="120" language="9" name="Staryu" genus="Star Shape">Staryu apparently communicates with the stars in the night sky
by flashing the red core at the center of its body. If parts of its
body are torn, this Pokémon simply regenerates the missing
pieces and limbs.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="121" language="9" name="Starmie" genus="Mysterious">Starmie swims through water by spinning its star-shaped
body as if it were a propeller on a ship. The core at the
center of this Pokémon’s body glows in seven colors.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="122" language="9" name="Mr. Mime" genus="Barrier">Mr. Mime is a master of pantomime. Its gestures and motions
convince watchers that something unseeable actually exists.
Once the watchers are convinced, the unseeable thing exists
as if it were real.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="123" language="9" name="Scyther" genus="Mantis">Scyther is blindingly fast. Its blazing speed enhances the
effectiveness of the twin scythes on its forearms. This
Pokémon’s scythes are so effective, they can slice through
thick logs in one wicked stroke.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="124" language="9" name="Jynx" genus="Human Shape">Jynx walks rhythmically, swaying and shaking its hips
as if it were dancing. Its motions are so bouncingly alluring,
people seeing it are compelled to shake their hips without
giving any thought to what they are doing.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="125" language="9" name="Electabuzz" genus="Electric">When a storm arrives, gangs of this Pokémon compete with
each other to scale heights that are likely to be stricken by
lightning bolts. Some towns use Electabuzz in place of
lightning rods.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="126" language="9" name="Magmar" genus="Spitfire">In battle, Magmar blows out intensely hot flames from
all over its body to intimidate its opponent. This Pokémon’s
fiery bursts create heat waves that ignite grass and trees in
its surroundings.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="127" language="9" name="Pinsir" genus="Stag Beetle">Pinsir has a pair of massive horns. Protruding from the surface
of these horns are thorns. These thorns are driven deeply into
the foe’s body when the pincer closes, making it tough for the
foe to escape.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="128" language="9" name="Tauros" genus="Wild Bull">This Pokémon is not satisfied unless it is rampaging at all
times. If there is no opponent for Tauros to battle, it will
charge at thick trees and knock them down to calm itself.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="129" language="9" name="Magikarp" genus="Fish">Magikarp is virtually useless in battle as it can only splash
around. As a result, it is considered to be weak. However,
it is actually a very hardy Pokémon that can survive in any
body of water no matter how polluted it is.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="130" language="9" name="Gyarados" genus="Atrocious">Once Gyarados goes on a rampage, its ferociously violent
blood doesn’t calm until it has burned everything down.
There are records of this Pokémon’s rampages lasting a
whole month.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="131" language="9" name="Lapras" genus="Transport">People have driven Lapras almost to the point of extinction.
In the evenings, this Pokémon is said to sing plaintively as
it seeks what few others of its kind still remain.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="132" language="9" name="Ditto" genus="Transform">Ditto rearranges its cell structure to transform itself into other
shapes. However, if it tries to transform itself into something
by relying on its memory, this Pokémon manages to get
details wrong.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="133" language="9" name="Eevee" genus="Evolution">Eevee has an unstable genetic makeup that suddenly mutates
due to the environment in which it lives. Radiation from various
stones causes this Pokémon to evolve.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="134" language="9" name="Vaporeon" genus="Bubble Jet">Vaporeon underwent a spontaneous mutation and grew fins
and gills that allow it to live underwater. This Pokémon has
the ability to freely control water.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="135" language="9" name="Jolteon" genus="Lightning">Jolteon’s cells generate a low level of electricity. This power
is amplified by the static electricity of its fur, enabling the
Pokémon to drop thunderbolts. The bristling fur is made of
electrically charged needles.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="136" language="9" name="Flareon" genus="Flame">Flareon’s fluffy fur has a functional purpose—it releases heat
into the air so that its body does not get excessively hot.
This Pokémon’s body temperature can rise to a maximum of
1,650 degrees Fahrenheit.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="137" language="9" name="Porygon" genus="Virtual">Porygon is capable of reverting itself entirely back to program
data and entering cyberspace. This Pokémon is copy protected
so it cannot be duplicated by copying.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="138" language="9" name="Omanyte" genus="Spiral">Omanyte is one of the ancient and long-since-extinct Pokémon
that have been regenerated from fossils by people. If attacked
by an enemy, it withdraws itself inside its hard shell.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="139" language="9" name="Omastar" genus="Spiral">Omastar uses its tentacles to capture its prey. It is
believed to have become extinct because its shell grew too
large and heavy, causing its movements to become too slow
and ponderous.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="140" language="9" name="Kabuto" genus="Shellfish">Kabuto is a Pokémon that has been regenerated from a fossil.
However, in extremely rare cases, living examples have
been discovered. The Pokémon has not changed at all for
300 million years.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="141" language="9" name="Kabutops" genus="Shellfish">Kabutops swam underwater to hunt for its prey in ancient
times. The Pokémon was apparently evolving from being a
water dweller to living on land as evident from the beginnings
of change in its gills and legs.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="142" language="9" name="Aerodactyl" genus="Fossil">Aerodactyl is a Pokémon from the age of dinosaurs. It was
regenerated from genetic material extracted from amber. It is
imagined to have been the king of the skies in ancient times.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="143" language="9" name="Snorlax" genus="Sleeping">Snorlax’s typical day consists of nothing more than eating and
sleeping. It is such a docile Pokémon that there are children
who use its expansive belly as a place to play.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="144" language="9" name="Articuno" genus="Freeze">Articuno is a legendary bird Pokémon that can control ice.
The flapping of its wings chills the air. As a result, it is said
that when this Pokémon flies, snow will fall.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="145" language="9" name="Zapdos" genus="Electric">Zapdos is a legendary bird Pokémon that has the ability
to control electricity. It usually lives in thunderclouds.
The Pokémon gains power if it is stricken by lightning bolts.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="146" language="9" name="Moltres" genus="Flame">Moltres is a legendary bird Pokémon that has the ability
to control fire. If this Pokémon is injured, it is said to dip its
body in the molten magma of a volcano to burn and heal itself.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="147" language="9" name="Dratini" genus="Dragon">Dratini continually molts and sloughs off its old skin. It does so
because the life energy within its body steadily builds to reach
uncontrollable levels.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="148" language="9" name="Dragonair" genus="Dragon">Dragonair stores an enormous amount of energy inside
its body. It is said to alter weather conditions in its vicinity
by discharging energy from the crystals on its neck and tail.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="149" language="9" name="Dragonite" genus="Dragon">Dragonite is capable of circling the globe in just 16 hours.
It is a kindhearted Pokémon that leads lost and foundering
ships in a storm to the safety of land.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="150" language="9" name="Mewtwo" genus="Genetic">Mewtwo is a Pokémon that was created by genetic
manipulation. However, even though the scientific power
of humans created this Pokémon’s body, they failed to
endow Mewtwo with a compassionate heart.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="151" language="9" name="Mew" genus="New Species">Mew is said to possess the genetic composition of all
Pokémon. It is capable of making itself invisible at will,
so it entirely avoids notice even if it approaches people.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="152" language="9" name="Chikorita" genus="Leaf">In battle, Chikorita waves its leaf around to keep the foe at
bay. However, a sweet fragrance also wafts from the leaf,
becalming the battling Pokémon and creating a cozy,
friendly atmosphere all around.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="153" language="9" name="Bayleef" genus="Leaf">Bayleef’s neck is ringed by curled-up leaves. Inside each
tubular leaf is a small shoot of a tree. The fragrance of this
shoot makes people peppy.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="154" language="9" name="Meganium" genus="Herb">The fragrance of Meganium’s flower soothes and calms
emotions. In battle, this Pokémon gives off more of its
becalming scent to blunt the foe’s fighting spirit.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="155" language="9" name="Cyndaquil" genus="Fire Mouse">Cyndaquil protects itself by flaring up the flames on its back.
The flames are vigorous if the Pokémon is angry. However, if it
is tired, the flames splutter fitfully with incomplete combustion.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="156" language="9" name="Quilava" genus="Volcano">Quilava keeps its foes at bay with the intensity of its flames
and gusts of superheated air. This Pokémon applies its
outstanding nimbleness to dodge attacks even while scorching
the foe with flames.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="157" language="9" name="Typhlosion" genus="Volcano">Typhlosion obscures itself behind a shimmering heat haze that
it creates using its intensely hot flames. This Pokémon creates
blazing explosive blasts that burn everything to cinders.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="158" language="9" name="Totodile" genus="Big Jaw">Despite the smallness of its body, Totodile’s jaws are very
powerful. While the Pokémon may think it is just playfully
nipping, its bite has enough power to cause serious injury.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="159" language="9" name="Croconaw" genus="Big Jaw">Once Croconaw has clamped its jaws on its foe, it will
absolutely not let go. Because the tips of its fangs are
forked back like barbed fishhooks, they become impossible
to remove when they have sunk in.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="160" language="9" name="Feraligatr" genus="Big Jaw">Feraligatr intimidates its foes by opening its huge mouth.
In battle, it will kick the ground hard with its thick and powerful
hind legs to charge at the foe at an incredible speed.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="161" language="9" name="Sentret" genus="Scout">When Sentret sleeps, it does so while another stands guard.
The sentry wakes the others at the first sign of danger. When
this Pokémon becomes separated from its pack, it becomes
incapable of sleep due to fear.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="162" language="9" name="Furret" genus="Long Body">Furret has a very slim build. When under attack, it can slickly
squirm through narrow spaces and get away. In spite of its
short limbs, this Pokémon is very nimble and fleet.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="163" language="9" name="Hoothoot" genus="Owl">Hoothoot has an internal organ that senses and tracks the
earth’s rotation. Using this special organ, this Pokémon
begins hooting at precisely the same time every day.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="164" language="9" name="Noctowl" genus="Owl">Noctowl never fails at catching prey in darkness. This Pokémon
owes its success to its superior vision that allows it to see in
minimal light, and to its soft, supple wings that make no sound
in flight.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="165" language="9" name="Ledyba" genus="Five Star">Ledyba secretes an aromatic fluid from where its legs join its
body. This fluid is used for communicating with others.
This Pokémon conveys its feelings to others by altering the
fluid’s scent.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="166" language="9" name="Ledian" genus="Five Star">It is said that in lands with clean air, where the stars fill the
sky, there live Ledian in countless numbers. There is a good
reason for this—the Pokémon uses the light of the stars as
its energy.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="167" language="9" name="Spinarak" genus="String Spit">The web spun by Spinarak can be considered its second
nervous system. It is said that this Pokémon can determine
what kind of prey is touching its web just by the tiny vibrations
it feels through the web’s strands.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="168" language="9" name="Ariados" genus="Long Leg">Ariados’s feet are tipped with tiny hooked claws that enable it
to scuttle on ceilings and vertical walls. This Pokémon
constricts the foe with thin and strong silk webbing.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="169" language="9" name="Crobat" genus="Bat">Crobat sneaks up on its intended prey using wings that barely
make a sound. This Pokémon rests by hanging on a tree
branch with its rear legs that serve as wings.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="170" language="9" name="Chinchou" genus="Angler">Chinchou’s two antennas are filled with cells that generate
strong electricity. This Pokémon’s cells create so much
electrical power, it even makes itself tingle slightly.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="171" language="9" name="Lanturn" genus="Light">Lanturn is known to emit light. If you peer down into the dark
sea from a ship at night, you can sometimes see this
Pokémon’s light rising from the depths where it swims. It gives
the sea an appearance of a starlit night.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="172" language="9" name="Pichu" genus="Tiny Mouse">When Pichu plays with others, it may short out electricity with
another Pichu, creating a shower of sparks. In that event, this
Pokémon will begin crying, startled by the flash of sparks.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="173" language="9" name="Cleffa" genus="Star Shape">On nights with many shooting stars, Cleffa can be seen
dancing in a ring. They dance through the night and stop only
at the break of day, when these Pokémon quench their thirst
with the morning dew.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="174" language="9" name="Igglybuff" genus="Balloon">Igglybuff has a soft and plushy body that feels very much like
a marshmallow. From this body wafts a gently sweet fragrance
that soothes and calms the emotions of its foes.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="175" language="9" name="Togepi" genus="Spike Ball">As its energy, Togepi uses the positive emotions of
compassion and pleasure exuded by people and Pokémon.
This Pokémon stores up feelings of happiness inside its shell,
then shares them with others.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="176" language="9" name="Togetic" genus="Happiness">Togetic is said to be a Pokémon that brings good fortune.
When the Pokémon spots someone who is pure of heart,
it is said to appear and share its happiness with that person.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="177" language="9" name="Natu" genus="Tiny Bird">Natu has a highly developed jumping ability. The Pokémon
flaps and leaps onto tree branches that are taller than
grown-up people to pick at the tree’s new shoots.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="178" language="9" name="Xatu" genus="Mystic">Xatu is known to stand motionless while staring at the sun all
day long. Some people revere it as a mystical Pokémon out of
their belief that Xatu is in possession of the power to see into
the future.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="179" language="9" name="Mareep" genus="Wool">Mareep’s fluffy coat of wool rubs together and builds a static
charge. The more static electricity is charged, the more brightly
the lightbulb at the tip of its tail glows.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="180" language="9" name="Flaaffy" genus="Wool">Flaaffy’s wool quality changes so that it can generate
a high amount of static electricity with a small amount of
wool. The bare and slick parts of its hide are shielded
against electricity.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="181" language="9" name="Ampharos" genus="Light">Ampharos gives off so much light that it can be seen even from
space. People in the old days used the light of this Pokémon
to send signals back and forth with others far away.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="182" language="9" name="Bellossom" genus="Flower">A Bellossom grows flowers more beautifully if it has evolved
from a smelly Gloom—the more stinky the better. At night, this
Pokémon closes its petals and goes to sleep.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="183" language="9" name="Marill" genus="Aqua Mouse">When fishing for food at the edge of a fast-running stream,
Marill wraps its tail around the trunk of a tree. This Pokémon’s
tail is flexible and configured to stretch.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="184" language="9" name="Azumarill" genus="Aqua Rabbit">Azumarill can make balloons out of air. It makes these air
balloons if it spots a drowning Pokémon. The air balloons
enable the Pokémon in trouble to breathe.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="185" language="9" name="Sudowoodo" genus="Imitation">Sudowoodo camouflages itself as a tree to avoid being
attacked by enemies. However, because its hands remain
green throughout the year, the Pokémon is easily identified
as a fake during the winter.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="186" language="9" name="Politoed" genus="Frog">The curled hair on Politoed’s head is proof of its status as a
king. It is said that the longer and more curled the hair, the
more respect this Pokémon earns from its peers.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="187" language="9" name="Hoppip" genus="Cottonweed">This Pokémon drifts and floats with the wind. If it senses the
approach of strong winds, Hoppip links its leaves with other
Hoppip to prepare against being blown away.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="188" language="9" name="Skiploom" genus="Cottonweed">Skiploom’s flower blossoms when the temperature rises
above 64 degrees Fahrenheit. How much the flower opens
depends on the temperature. For that reason, this Pokémon
is sometimes used as a thermometer.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="189" language="9" name="Jumpluff" genus="Cottonweed">Jumpluff rides warm southern winds to cross the sea and fly to
foreign lands. The Pokémon descends to the ground when it
encounters cold air while it is floating.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="190" language="9" name="Aipom" genus="Long Tail">Aipom’s tail ends in a hand-like appendage that can be cleverly
manipulated. However, because the Pokémon uses its tail so
much, its real hands have become rather clumsy.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="191" language="9" name="Sunkern" genus="Seed">Sunkern tries to move as little as it possibly can. It does so
because it tries to conserve all the nutrients it has stored in its
body for its evolution. It will not eat a thing, subsisting only on
morning dew.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="192" language="9" name="Sunflora" genus="Sun">Sunflora converts solar energy into nutrition. It moves around
actively in the daytime when it is warm. It stops moving as
soon as the sun goes down for the night.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="193" language="9" name="Yanma" genus="Clear Wing">Yanma is capable of seeing 360 degrees without having to
move its eyes. It is a great flier that is adept at making sudden
stops and turning midair. This Pokémon uses its flying ability
to quickly chase down targeted prey.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="194" language="9" name="Wooper" genus="Water Fish">Wooper usually lives in water. However, it occasionally comes
out onto land in search of food. On land, it coats its body with
a gooey, toxic film.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="195" language="9" name="Quagsire" genus="Water Fish">Quagsire hunts for food by leaving its mouth wide open in
water and waiting for its prey to blunder in unaware. Because
the Pokémon does not move, it does not get very hungry.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="196" language="9" name="Espeon" genus="Sun">Espeon is extremely loyal to any Trainer it considers to
be worthy. It is said that this Pokémon developed its
precognitive powers to protect its Trainer from harm.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="197" language="9" name="Umbreon" genus="Moonlight">Umbreon evolved as a result of exposure to the moon’s waves.
It hides silently in darkness and waits for its foes to make a
move. The rings on its body glow when it leaps to attack.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="198" language="9" name="Murkrow" genus="Darkness">Murkrow was feared and loathed as the alleged bearer of ill
fortune. This Pokémon shows strong interest in anything that
sparkles or glitters. It will even try to steal rings from women.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="199" language="9" name="Slowking" genus="Royal">Slowking undertakes research every day in an effort to solve
the mysteries of the world. However, this Pokémon apparently
forgets everything it has learned if the Shellder on its head
comes off.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="200" language="9" name="Misdreavus" genus="Screech">Misdreavus frightens people with a creepy, sobbing cry.
The Pokémon apparently uses its red spheres to absorb the
fearful feelings of foes and turn them into nutrition.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="201" language="9" name="Unown" genus="Symbol">This Pokémon is shaped like ancient writing. It is a mystery as
to which came first, the ancient writings or the various Unown.
Research into this topic is ongoing but nothing is known.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="202" language="9" name="Wobbuffet" genus="Patient">Wobbuffet does nothing but endure attacks—it won’t attack on
its own. However, it won’t endure an attack on its tail. When
that happens, the Pokémon will try to take the foe with it using
Destiny Bond.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="203" language="9" name="Girafarig" genus="Long Neck">Girafarig’s rear head contains a tiny brain that is too small for
thinking. However, the rear head doesn’t need to sleep, so it
can keep watch over its surroundings 24 hours a day.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="204" language="9" name="Pineco" genus="Bagworm">Pineco hangs from a tree branch and patiently waits for prey to
come along. If the Pokémon is disturbed while eating by
someone shaking its tree, it drops down to the ground and
explodes with no warning.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="205" language="9" name="Forretress" genus="Bagworm">Forretress conceals itself inside its hardened steel shell.
The shell is opened when the Pokémon is catching prey,
but it does so at such a quick pace that the shell’s inside
cannot be seen.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="206" language="9" name="Dunsparce" genus="Land Snake">Dunsparce has a drill for its tail. It uses this tail to burrow into
the ground backward. This Pokémon is known to make its
nest in complex shapes deep under the ground.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="207" language="9" name="Gligar" genus="Fly Scorpion">Gligar glides through the air without a sound as if it were
sliding. This Pokémon hangs on to the face of its foe using
its clawed hind legs and the large pincers on its forelegs, then
injects the prey with its poison barb.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="208" language="9" name="Steelix" genus="Iron Snake">Steelix lives even further underground than Onix.
This Pokémon is known to dig toward the earth’s core.
There are records of this Pokémon reaching a depth of
over six-tenths of a mile underground.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="209" language="9" name="Snubbull" genus="Fairy">By baring its fangs and making a scary face, Snubbull sends
smaller Pokémon scurrying away in terror. However, this
Pokémon seems a little sad at making its foes flee.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="210" language="9" name="Granbull" genus="Fairy">Granbull has a particularly well-developed lower jaw.
The enormous fangs are heavy, causing the Pokémon to tip
its head back for balance. Unless it is startled, it will not try to
bite indiscriminately.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="211" language="9" name="Qwilfish" genus="Balloon">Qwilfish sucks in water, inflating itself. This Pokémon
uses the pressure of the water it swallowed to shoot toxic
quills all at once from all over its body. It finds swimming
somewhat challenging.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="212" language="9" name="Scizor" genus="Pincer">Scizor has a body with the hardness of steel. It is not easily
fazed by ordinary sorts of attacks. This Pokémon flaps its
wings to regulate its body temperature.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="213" language="9" name="Shuckle" genus="Mold">Shuckle quietly hides itself under rocks, keeping its body
concealed inside its hard shell while eating berries it has
stored away. The berries mix with its body fluids to become
a juice.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="214" language="9" name="Heracross" genus="Single Horn">Heracross has sharp claws on its feet. These are planted
firmly into the ground or the bark of a tree, giving the
Pokémon a secure and solid footing to forcefully fling away
foes with its proud horn.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="215" language="9" name="Sneasel" genus="Sharp Claw">Sneasel scales trees by punching its hooked claws into the
bark. This Pokémon seeks out unguarded nests and steals
eggs for food while the parents are away.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="216" language="9" name="Teddiursa" genus="Little Bear">This Pokémon likes to lick its palms that are sweetened by
being soaked in honey. Teddiursa concocts its own honey
by blending fruits and pollen collected by Beedrill.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="217" language="9" name="Ursaring" genus="Hibernator">In the forests inhabited by Ursaring, it is said that there are
many streams and towering trees where they gather food. This
Pokémon walks through its forest gathering food every day.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="218" language="9" name="Slugma" genus="Lava">Slugma does not have any blood in its body. Instead, intensely
hot magma circulates throughout this Pokémon’s body,
carrying essential nutrients and oxygen to its organs.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="219" language="9" name="Magcargo" genus="Lava">Magcargo’s body temperature is approximately
18,000 degrees Fahrenheit. Water is vaporized on contact.
If this Pokémon is caught in the rain, the raindrops instantly
turn into steam, cloaking the area in a thick fog.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="220" language="9" name="Swinub" genus="Pig">Swinub roots for food by rubbing its snout against the ground.
Its favorite food is a mushroom that grows under the cover of
dead grass. This Pokémon occasionally roots out hot springs.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="221" language="9" name="Piloswine" genus="Swine">Piloswine is covered by a thick coat of long hair that enables
it to endure the freezing cold. This Pokémon uses its tusks to
dig up food that has been buried under ice.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="222" language="9" name="Corsola" genus="Coral">Clusters of Corsola congregate in warm seas where they serve
as ideal hiding places for smaller Pokémon. When the water
temperature falls, this Pokémon migrates to the southern seas.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="223" language="9" name="Remoraid" genus="Jet">Remoraid sucks in water, then expels it at high velocity using
its abdominal muscles to shoot down flying prey. When
evolution draws near, this Pokémon travels downstream
from rivers.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="224" language="9" name="Octillery" genus="Jet">Octillery grabs onto its foe using its tentacles. This Pokémon
tries to immobilize it before delivering the finishing blow. If the
foe turns out to be too strong, Octillery spews ink to escape.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="225" language="9" name="Delibird" genus="Delivery">Delibird carries its food bundled up in its tail. There once was
a famous explorer who managed to reach the peak of the
world’s highest mountain, thanks to one of these Pokémon
sharing its food.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="226" language="9" name="Mantine" genus="Kite">On sunny days, schools of Mantine can be seen elegantly
leaping over the sea’s waves. This Pokémon is not bothered
by the Remoraid that hitches rides.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="227" language="9" name="Skarmory" genus="Armor Bird">Skarmory’s steel wings become tattered and bashed in from
repeated battles. Once a year, the battered wings grow back
completely, restoring the cutting edges to their pristine state.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="228" language="9" name="Houndour" genus="Dark">Houndour hunt as a coordinated pack. They communicate
with each other using a variety of cries to corner their prey.
This Pokémon’s remarkable teamwork is unparalleled.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="229" language="9" name="Houndoom" genus="Dark">In a Houndoom pack, the one with its horns raked sharply
toward the back serves a leadership role. These Pokémon
choose their leader by fighting among themselves.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="230" language="9" name="Kingdra" genus="Dragon">Kingdra sleeps on the seafloor where it is otherwise devoid
of life. When a storm arrives, the Pokémon is said to awaken
and wander about in search of prey.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="231" language="9" name="Phanpy" genus="Long Nose">Phanpy uses its long nose to shower itself. When others
gather around, they thoroughly douse each other with water.
These Pokémon can be seen drying their soaking-wet
bodies at the edge of water.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="232" language="9" name="Donphan" genus="Armor">If Donphan were to tackle with its hard body, even a house
could be destroyed. Using its massive strength, the Pokémon
helps clear rock and mud slides that block mountain trails.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="233" language="9" name="Porygon2" genus="Virtual">Porygon2 was created by humans using the power of science.
The man-made Pokémon has been endowed with artificial
intelligence that enables it to learn new gestures and emotions
on its own.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="234" language="9" name="Stantler" genus="Big Horn">Stantler’s magnificent antlers were traded at high prices as
works of art. As a result, this Pokémon was hunted close to
extinction by those who were after the priceless antlers.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="235" language="9" name="Smeargle" genus="Painter">Smeargle marks the boundaries of its territory using a body
fluid that leaks out from the tip of its tail. Over 5,000 different
marks left by this Pokémon have been found.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="236" language="9" name="Tyrogue" genus="Scuffle">Tyrogue becomes stressed out if it does not get to train every
day. When raising this Pokémon, the Trainer must establish
and uphold various training methods.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="237" language="9" name="Hitmontop" genus="Handstand">Hitmontop spins on its head at high speed, all the while
delivering kicks. This technique is a remarkable mix of both
offense and defense at the same time. The Pokémon travels
faster spinning than it does walking.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="238" language="9" name="Smoochum" genus="Kiss">Smoochum actively runs about, but also falls quite often.
Whenever the chance arrives, it will look for its reflection to
make sure its face hasn’t become dirty.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="239" language="9" name="Elekid" genus="Electric">Elekid stores electricity in its body. If it touches metal and
accidentally discharges all its built-up electricity, this Pokémon
begins swinging its arms in circles to recharge itself.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="240" language="9" name="Magby" genus="Live Coal">Magby’s state of health is determined by observing the fire it
breathes. If the Pokémon is spouting yellow flames from its
mouth, it is in good health. When it is fatigued, black smoke
will be mixed in with the flames.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="241" language="9" name="Miltank" genus="Milk Cow">Miltank gives over five gallons of milk on a daily basis. Its
sweet milk is enjoyed by children and grown-ups alike. People
who can’t drink milk turn it into yogurt and eat it instead.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="242" language="9" name="Blissey" genus="Happiness">Blissey senses sadness with its fluffy coat of fur. If it does so,
this Pokémon will rush over to a sad person, no matter how far
away, to share a Lucky Egg that brings a smile to any face.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="243" language="9" name="Raikou" genus="Thunder">Raikou embodies the speed of lightning. The roars of
this Pokémon send shock waves shuddering through the
air and shake the ground as if lightning bolts had come
crashing down.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="244" language="9" name="Entei" genus="Volcano">Entei embodies the passion of magma. This Pokémon is
thought to have been born in the eruption of a volcano.
It sends up massive bursts of fire that utterly consume all
that they touch.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="245" language="9" name="Suicune" genus="Aurora">Suicune embodies the compassion of a pure spring of water.
It runs across the land with gracefulness. This Pokémon has
the power to purify dirty water.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="246" language="9" name="Larvitar" genus="Rock Skin">Larvitar is born deep under the ground. To come up to the
surface, this Pokémon must eat its way through the soil above.
Until it does so, Larvitar cannot see its parents.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="247" language="9" name="Pupitar" genus="Hard Shell">Pupitar creates a gas inside its body that it compresses and
forcefully ejects to propel itself like a jet. The body is very
durable—it avoids damage even if it hits solid steel.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="248" language="9" name="Tyranitar" genus="Armor">Tyranitar is so overwhelmingly powerful, it can bring down a
whole mountain to make its nest. This Pokémon wanders about
in mountains seeking new opponents to fight.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="249" language="9" name="Lugia" genus="Diving">Lugia’s wings pack devastating power—a light fluttering of its
wings can blow apart regular houses. As a result, this
Pokémon chooses to live out of sight deep under the sea.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="250" language="9" name="Ho-Oh" genus="Rainbow">Ho-Oh’s feathers glow in seven colors depending on the angle
at which they are struck by light. These feathers are said to
bring happiness to the bearers. This Pokémon is said to live at
the foot of a rainbow.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="251" language="9" name="Celebi" genus="Time Travel">This Pokémon came from the future by crossing over time.
It is thought that so long as Celebi appears, a bright and
shining future awaits us.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="252" language="9" name="Treecko" genus="Wood Gecko">Treecko is cool, calm, and collected—it never panics under
any situation. If a bigger foe were to glare at this Pokémon,
it would glare right back without conceding an inch of ground.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="253" language="9" name="Grovyle" genus="Wood Gecko">This Pokémon adeptly flies from branch to branch in trees.
In a forest, no Pokémon can ever hope to catch a fleeing
Grovyle however fast they may be.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="254" language="9" name="Sceptile" genus="Forest">Sceptile has seeds growing on its back. They are said to be
bursting with nutrients that revitalize trees. This Pokémon
raises the trees in a forest with loving care.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="255" language="9" name="Torchic" genus="Chick">Torchic has a place inside its body where it keeps its flame.
Give it a hug—it will be glowing with warmth. This Pokémon is
covered all over by a fluffy coat of down.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="256" language="9" name="Combusken" genus="Young Fowl">Combusken battles with the intensely hot flames it spews from
its beak and with outstandingly destructive kicks. This
Pokémon’s cry is very loud and distracting.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="257" language="9" name="Blaziken" genus="Blaze">Blaziken has incredibly strong legs—it can easily clear a
30-story building in one leap. This Pokémon’s blazing punches
leave its foes scorched and blackened.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="258" language="9" name="Mudkip" genus="Mud Fish">In water, Mudkip breathes using the gills on its cheeks. If it is
faced with a tight situation in battle, this Pokémon will unleash
its amazing power—it can crush rocks bigger than itself.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="259" language="9" name="Marshtomp" genus="Mud Fish">Marshtomp is much faster at traveling through mud than it is at
swimming. This Pokémon’s hindquarters exhibit obvious
development, giving it the ability to walk on just its hind legs.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="260" language="9" name="Swampert" genus="Mud Fish">Swampert predicts storms by sensing subtle differences in the
sounds of waves and tidal winds with its fins. If a storm is
approaching, it piles up boulders to protect itself.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="261" language="9" name="Poochyena" genus="Bite">Poochyena is an omnivore—it will eat anything. A distinguishing
feature is how large its fangs are compared to its body. This
Pokémon tries to intimidate its foes by making the hair on its
tail bristle out.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="262" language="9" name="Mightyena" genus="Bite">Mightyena travel and act as a pack in the wild. The memory
of its life in the wild compels the Pokémon to obey only
those Trainers that it recognizes to possess superior skill.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="263" language="9" name="Zigzagoon" genus="Tiny Raccoon">The hair on Zigzagoon’s back is bristly. It rubs the hard back
hair against trees to leave its territorial markings. This Pokémon
may play dead to fool foes in battle.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="264" language="9" name="Linoone" genus="Rushing">When hunting, Linoone will make a beeline straight for the
prey at a full run. While this Pokémon is capable of topping
60 mph, it has to come to a screeching halt before it can turn.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="265" language="9" name="Wurmple" genus="Worm">Wurmple is targeted by Swellow as prey. This Pokémon
will try to resist by pointing the spikes on its rear at the
attacking predator. It will weaken the foe by leaking poison
from the spikes.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="266" language="9" name="Silcoon" genus="Cocoon">Silcoon was thought to endure hunger and not consume
anything before its evolution. However, it is now thought
that this Pokémon slakes its thirst by drinking rainwater
that collects on its silk.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="267" language="9" name="Beautifly" genus="Butterfly">Beautifly has a long mouth like a coiled needle, which is very
convenient for collecting pollen from flowers. This Pokémon
rides the spring winds as it flits around gathering pollen.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="268" language="9" name="Cascoon" genus="Cocoon">If it is attacked, Cascoon remains motionless however badly it
may be hurt. It does so because if it were to move, its body
would be weak upon evolution. This Pokémon will also not
forget the pain it endured.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="269" language="9" name="Dustox" genus="Poison Moth">When Dustox flaps its wings, a fine dust is scattered all over.
This dust is actually a powerful poison that will even make a
pro wrestler sick. This Pokémon searches for food using its
antennae like radar.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="270" language="9" name="Lotad" genus="Water Weed">Lotad is said to have dwelled on land before. However, this
Pokémon is thought to have returned to water because the
leaf on its head grew large and heavy. It now lives by floating
atop the water.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="271" language="9" name="Lombre" genus="Jolly">Lombre’s entire body is covered by a slippery, slimy film.
It feels horribly unpleasant to be touched by this Pokémon’s
hands. Lombre is often mistaken for a human child.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="272" language="9" name="Ludicolo" genus="Carefree">Upon hearing an upbeat and cheerful rhythm, the cells in
Ludicolo’s body become very energetic and active. Even
in battle, this Pokémon will exhibit an amazing amount
of power.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="273" language="9" name="Seedot" genus="Acorn">Seedot looks exactly like an acorn when it is dangling from a
tree branch. It startles other Pokémon by suddenly moving.
This Pokémon polishes its body once a day using leaves.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="274" language="9" name="Nuzleaf" genus="Wily">This Pokémon pulls out the leaf on its head and makes a flute
with it. The sound of Nuzleaf’s flute strikes fear and uncertainty
in the hearts of people lost in a forest.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="275" language="9" name="Shiftry" genus="Wicked">Shiftry’s large fans generate awesome gusts of wind at a
speed close to 100 feet per second. The whipped-up wind
blows anything away. This Pokémon chooses to live quietly
deep in forests.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="276" language="9" name="Taillow" genus="Tiny Swallow">Taillow is young—it has only just left its nest. As a result,
it sometimes becomes lonesome and cries at night.
This Pokémon feeds on Wurmple that live in forests.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="277" language="9" name="Swellow" genus="Swallow">Swellow is very conscientious about the upkeep of its glossy
wings. Once two Swellow are gathered, they diligently take
care of cleaning each other’s wings.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="278" language="9" name="Wingull" genus="Seagull">Wingull rides updrafts rising from the sea by extending its long
and narrow wings to glide. This Pokémon’s long beak is useful
for catching prey.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="279" language="9" name="Pelipper" genus="Water Bird">Pelipper searches for food while in flight by skimming the wave
tops. This Pokémon dips its large bill in the sea to scoop up
food, then swallows everything in one big gulp.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="280" language="9" name="Ralts" genus="Feeling">Ralts has the ability to sense the emotions of people. If its
Trainer is in a cheerful mood, this Pokémon grows cheerful
and joyous in the same way.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="281" language="9" name="Kirlia" genus="Emotion">Kirlia uses the horns on its head to amplify its psychokinetic
power. When the Pokémon uses its power, the air around it
becomes distorted, creating mirages of nonexistent scenery.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="282" language="9" name="Gardevoir" genus="Embrace">Gardevoir has the psychokinetic power to distort the
dimensions and create a small black hole. This Pokémon
will try to protect its Trainer even at the risk of its own life.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="283" language="9" name="Surskit" genus="Pond Skater">If Surskit senses danger, it secretes a thick, sugary syrup from
the tip of its head. There are some Pokémon that love eating
this syrup.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="284" language="9" name="Masquerain" genus="Eyeball">Masquerain’s antennas have eyelike patterns that usually
give it an angry look. If the “eyes” are droopy and appear sad,
it is said to be a sign that a heavy rainfall is on its way.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="285" language="9" name="Shroomish" genus="Mushroom">If Shroomish senses danger, it shakes its body and scatters
spores from the top of its head. This Pokémon’s spores are
so toxic, they make trees and weeds wilt.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="286" language="9" name="Breloom" genus="Mushroom">The seeds ringing Breloom’s tail are made of hardened toxic
spores. It is horrible to eat the seeds. Just taking a bite of this
Pokémon’s seed will cause your stomach to rumble.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="287" language="9" name="Slakoth" genus="Slacker">Slakoth’s heart beats just once a minute. Whatever happens,
it is content to loaf around motionless. It is rare to see this
Pokémon in motion.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="288" language="9" name="Vigoroth" genus="Wild Monkey">Vigoroth is simply incapable of remaining still. Even when it
tries to sleep, the blood in its veins grows agitated, compelling
this Pokémon to run wild throughout the jungle before it can
settle down.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="289" language="9" name="Slaking" genus="Lazy">Wherever Slaking live, rings of over a yard in diameter appear
in grassy fields. They are made by the Pokémon as it eats all
the grass within reach while lying prone on the ground.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="290" language="9" name="Nincada" genus="Trainee">Nincada lives underground. It uses its sharp claws to carve the
roots of trees and absorb moisture and nutrients.
This Pokémon can’t withstand bright sunlight so avoids it.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="291" language="9" name="Ninjask" genus="Ninja">If Ninjask is not trained properly, it will refuse to obey
the Trainer and cry loudly continuously. Because of this
quality, this Pokémon is said to be one that puts the
Trainer’s abilities to the test.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="292" language="9" name="Shedinja" genus="Shed">Shedinja is a peculiar Pokémon. It seems to appear unsought
in a Poké Ball after a Nincada evolves. This bizarre Pokémon
is entirely immobile—it doesn’t even breathe.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="293" language="9" name="Whismur" genus="Whisper">Whismur is very timid. If it starts to cry loudly, it becomes
startled by its own crying and cries even harder. When it finally
stops crying, the Pokémon goes to sleep, all tired out.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="294" language="9" name="Loudred" genus="Big Voice">Loudred shouts while stamping its feet. After it finishes
shouting, this Pokémon becomes incapable of hearing
anything for a while. This is considered to be a weak point.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="295" language="9" name="Exploud" genus="Loud Noise">Exploud communicates its feelings to the others by emitting
whistle-like sounds from the tubes on its body. This Pokémon
only raises its voice when it is in battle.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="296" language="9" name="Makuhita" genus="Guts">Makuhita has a tireless spirit—it will never give up hope.
It eats a lot of food, gets plenty of sleep, and it trains very
rigorously. By living that way, this Pokémon packs its body
with energy.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="297" language="9" name="Hariyama" genus="Arm Thrust">Hariyama’s thick body may appear fat, but it is actually a hunk
of solid muscle. If this Pokémon bears down and tightens all its
muscles, its body becomes as hard as a rock.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="298" language="9" name="Azurill" genus="Polka Dot">Azurill’s tail is large and bouncy. It is packed full of the
nutrients this Pokémon needs to grow. Azurill can be seen
bouncing and playing on its big, rubbery tail.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="299" language="9" name="Nosepass" genus="Compass">Nosepass had been said to be completely unmoving, with its
magnetic nose pointed due north. However, close observation
has revealed that the Pokémon actually moves by a little over
3/8 of an inch every year.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="300" language="9" name="Skitty" genus="Kitten">Skitty is known to chase around playfully after its own tail.
In the wild, this Pokémon lives in holes in the trees of forests.
It is very popular as a pet because of its adorable looks.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="301" language="9" name="Delcatty" genus="Prim">Delcatty sleeps anywhere it wants without keeping a permanent
nest. If other Pokémon approach it as it sleeps, this Pokémon
will never fight—it will just move away somewhere else.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="302" language="9" name="Sableye" genus="Darkness">Sableye digs the ground with sharpened claws to find rocks
that it eats. Substances in the eaten rocks crystallize and rise
up to the Pokémon’s body surface.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="303" language="9" name="Mawile" genus="Deceiver">Don’t be taken in by this Pokémon’s cute face—it’s very
dangerous. Mawile fools the foe into letting down its guard,
then chomps down with its massive jaws. The steel jaws are
really horns that have been transformed.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="304" language="9" name="Aron" genus="Iron Armor">Aron has a body of steel. With one all-out charge, this
Pokémon can demolish even a heavy dump truck.
The destroyed dump truck then becomes a handy meal
for the Pokémon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="305" language="9" name="Lairon" genus="Iron Armor">Lairon feeds on iron contained in rocks and water. It makes
its nest on mountains where iron ore is buried. As a result,
the Pokémon often clashes with humans mining the iron ore.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="306" language="9" name="Aggron" genus="Iron Armor">Aggron is protective of its environment. If its mountain is
ravaged by a landslide or a fire, this Pokémon will haul
topsoil to the area, plant trees, and beautifully restore its
own territory.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="307" language="9" name="Meditite" genus="Meditate">Meditite heightens its inner energy through meditation.
It survives on just one berry a day. Minimal eating is another
aspect of this Pokémon’s training.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="308" language="9" name="Medicham" genus="Meditate">Through the power of meditation, Medicham developed its
sixth sense. It gained the ability to use psychokinetic powers.
This Pokémon is known to meditate for a whole month
without eating.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="309" language="9" name="Electrike" genus="Lightning">Electrike runs faster than the human eye can follow.
The friction from running is converted into electricity,
which is then stored in this Pokémon’s fur.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="310" language="9" name="Manectric" genus="Discharge">Manectric discharges strong electricity from its mane.
The mane is used for collecting electricity in the atmosphere.
This Pokémon creates thunderclouds above its head.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="311" language="9" name="Plusle" genus="Cheering">When Plusle is cheering on its partner, it flashes with electric
sparks from all over its body. If its partner loses, this Pokémon
cries loudly.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="312" language="9" name="Minun" genus="Cheering">Minun loves to cheer on its partner in battle. It gives off sparks
from its body while it is doing so. If its partner is in trouble,
this Pokémon gives off increasing amounts of sparks.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="313" language="9" name="Volbeat" genus="Firefly">Volbeat’s tail glows like a lightbulb. With other Volbeat,
it uses its tail to draw geometric shapes in the night sky.
This Pokémon loves the sweet aroma given off by Illumise.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="314" language="9" name="Illumise" genus="Firefly">Illumise leads a flight of illuminated Volbeat to draw signs in
the night sky. This Pokémon is said to earn greater respect
from its peers by composing more complex designs in the sky.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="315" language="9" name="Roselia" genus="Thorn">On extremely rare occasions, a Roselia is said to appear with
its flowers in unusual colors. The thorns on this Pokémon’s
head contain a vicious poison.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="316" language="9" name="Gulpin" genus="Stomach">Most of Gulpin’s body is made up of its stomach—its heart and
brain are very small in comparison. This Pokémon’s stomach
contains special enzymes that dissolve anything.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="317" language="9" name="Swalot" genus="Poison Bag">Swalot has no teeth, so what it eats, it swallows whole, no
matter what. Its cavernous mouth yawns widely. An automobile
tire could easily fit inside this Pokémon’s mouth.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="318" language="9" name="Carvanha" genus="Savage">If anything invades Carvanha’s territory, it will swarm and tear
at the intruder with its pointed fangs. On its own, however, this
Pokémon turns suddenly timid.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="319" language="9" name="Sharpedo" genus="Brutal">Sharpedo can swim at speeds of up to 75 mph by jetting
seawater out of its backside. This Pokémon’s drawback is its
inability to swim long distances.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="320" language="9" name="Wailmer" genus="Ball Whale">Wailmer can store water inside its body to transform itself
into a ball for bouncing around on the ground. By filling itself
up with more water, this Pokémon can elevate the height of
its bounces.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="321" language="9" name="Wailord" genus="Float Whale">When chasing prey, Wailord herds them by leaping out of the
water and making a humongous splash. It is breathtaking to
see this Pokémon leaping out of the sea with others in its pod.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="322" language="9" name="Numel" genus="Numb">Numel stores magma of almost 2,200 degrees Fahrenheit
within its body. If it gets wet, the magma cools and hardens.
In that event, the Pokémon’s body grows heavy and its
movements become sluggish.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="323" language="9" name="Camerupt" genus="Eruption">The humps on Camerupt’s back are formed by a transformation
of its bones. They sometimes blast out molten magma.
This Pokémon apparently erupts often when it is enraged.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="324" language="9" name="Torkoal" genus="Coal">Torkoal generates energy by burning coal. It grows weaker
as the fire dies down. When it is preparing for battle, this
Pokémon burns more coal.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="325" language="9" name="Spoink" genus="Bounce">Spoink keeps a pearl on top of its head. The pearl functions to
amplify this Pokémon’s psychokinetic powers. It is therefore on
a constant search for a bigger pearl.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="326" language="9" name="Grumpig" genus="Manipulate">Grumpig uses the black pearls on its body to wield
its fantastic powers. When it is doing so, it dances bizarrely.
This Pokémon’s black pearls are valuable as works of art.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="327" language="9" name="Spinda" genus="Spot Panda">No two Spinda are said to have identical spot patterns on their
hides. This Pokémon moves in a curious manner as if it is
stumbling in dizziness. Its lurching movements can cause the
opponent to become confused.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="328" language="9" name="Trapinch" genus="Ant Pit">Trapinch is a patient hunter. It digs an inescapable pit in a
desert and waits for its prey to come tumbling down. This
Pokémon can go a whole week without access to any water.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="329" language="9" name="Vibrava" genus="Vibration">Vibrava’s wings have not yet completed the process of
growing. Rather than flying long distances, they are more
useful for generating ultrasonic waves by vibrating.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="330" language="9" name="Flygon" genus="Mystic">Flygon whips up a sandstorm by flapping its wings. The wings
create a series of notes that sound like singing. Because the
“singing” is the only thing that can be heard in a sandstorm,
this Pokémon is said to be the desert spirit.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="331" language="9" name="Cacnea" genus="Cactus">The more arid and harsh the environment, the more pretty and
fragrant a flower Cacnea grows. This Pokémon battles by
wildly swinging its thorny arms.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="332" language="9" name="Cacturne" genus="Scarecrow">If a traveler is going through a desert in the thick of night,
Cacturne will follow in a ragtag group. The Pokémon are
biding their time, waiting for the traveler to tire and become
incapable of moving.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="333" language="9" name="Swablu" genus="Cotton Bird">Swablu loves to make things clean. If it spots something dirty,
it will wipe and polish it with its cottony wings. If its wings
become dirty, this Pokémon finds a stream and showers itself.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="334" language="9" name="Altaria" genus="Humming">Altaria sings in a gorgeous soprano. Its wings are like cotton
clouds. This Pokémon catches updrafts with its buoyant wings
and soars way up into the wild blue yonder.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="335" language="9" name="Zangoose" genus="Cat Ferret">Zangoose usually stays on all fours, but when angered, it gets
up on its hind legs and extends its claws. This Pokémon shares
a bitter rivalry with Seviper that dates back over generations.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="336" language="9" name="Seviper" genus="Fang Snake">Seviper’s swordlike tail serves two purposes—it slashes foes
and douses them with secreted poison. This Pokémon will not
give up its long-running blood feud with Zangoose.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="337" language="9" name="Lunatone" genus="Meteorite">Lunatone becomes active around the time of the full moon.
Instead of walking, it moves by floating in midair.
The Pokémon’s intimidating red eyes cause all those who
see it to become transfixed with fear.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="338" language="9" name="Solrock" genus="Meteorite">Sunlight is the source of Solrock’s power. It is said to possess
the ability to read the emotions of others. This Pokémon gives
off intense heat while rotating its body.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="339" language="9" name="Barboach" genus="Whiskers">Barboach’s body is covered with a slimy film. If a foe grabs it,
this Pokémon just slips out of the enemy’s grip. This Pokémon
grows weak if the slimy coating dries up.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="340" language="9" name="Whiscash" genus="Whiskers">If Whiscash goes on a wild rampage, it sets off a quake-like
tremor with a radius of over three miles. This Pokémon has
the ability to predict real earthquakes.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="341" language="9" name="Corphish" genus="Ruffian">Corphish catches prey with its sharp claws. It has no
likes or dislikes when it comes to food—it will eat anything.
This Pokémon has no trouble living in filthy water.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="342" language="9" name="Crawdaunt" genus="Rogue">Crawdaunt molts (sheds) its shell regularly. Immediately after
molting, its shell is soft and tender. Until the shell hardens,
this Pokémon hides in its streambed burrow to avoid attack
from its foes.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="343" language="9" name="Baltoy" genus="Clay Doll">As soon as it spots others of its kind, Baltoy congregates with
them and then begins crying noisily in unison. This Pokémon
sleeps while cleverly balancing itself on its one foot.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="344" language="9" name="Claydol" genus="Clay Doll">Claydol is an enigma that appeared from a clay statue made by
an ancient civilization dating back 20,000 years. This Pokémon
shoots beams from both its hands.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="345" language="9" name="Lileep" genus="Sea Lily">Lileep is an ancient Pokémon that was regenerated from a
fossil. It remains permanently anchored to a rock. From its
immobile perch, this Pokémon intently scans for prey with its
two eyes.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="346" language="9" name="Cradily" genus="Barnacle">Cradily’s body serves as an anchor, preventing it from being
washed away in rough seas. This Pokémon secretes a strong
digestive fluid from its tentacles.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="347" language="9" name="Anorith" genus="Old Shrimp">Anorith is said to be a type of Pokémon predecessor, with
eight wings at the sides of its body. This Pokémon swam in the
primordial sea by undulating these eight wings.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="348" language="9" name="Armaldo" genus="Plate">Armaldo is a Pokémon species that became extinct in
prehistoric times. This Pokémon is said to have walked
on its hind legs, which would have been more convenient
for life on land.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="349" language="9" name="Feebas" genus="Fish">While Feebas’s body is in tatters, it has a hardy and tenacious
life force that enables it to live anywhere. However, this
Pokémon is also slow and dimwitted, making it an easy catch.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="350" language="9" name="Milotic" genus="Tender">Milotic live at the bottom of large lakes. When this
Pokémon’s body glows a vivid pink, it releases a pulsing
wave of energy that brings soothing calm to troubled hearts.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="351" language="9" name="Castform" genus="Weather">Castform borrows the power of nature to transform itself
into the guises of the sun, rain, and snow-clouds.
This Pokémon’s feelings change with the weather.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="352" language="9" name="Kecleon" genus="Color Swap">Kecleon alters its body coloration to blend in with its
surroundings, allowing it to sneak up on its prey unnoticed.
Then it lashes out with its long, stretchy tongue to instantly
ensnare the unsuspecting target.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="353" language="9" name="Shuppet" genus="Puppet">Shuppet grows by feeding on dark emotions, such as
vengefulness and envy, in the hearts of people. It roams
through cities in search of grudges that taint people.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="354" language="9" name="Banette" genus="Marionette">A cursed energy permeated the stuffing of a discarded and
forgotten plush doll, giving it new life as Banette.
The Pokémon’s energy would escape if it were to ever open
its mouth.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="355" language="9" name="Duskull" genus="Requiem">Duskull wanders lost among the deep darkness of midnight.
There is an oft-told admonishment given to misbehaving
children that this Pokémon will spirit away bad children who
earn scoldings from their mothers.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="356" language="9" name="Dusclops" genus="Beckon">Dusclops absorbs anything, however large the object may be.
This Pokémon hypnotizes its foe by waving its hands in a
macabre manner and by bringing its single eye to bear.
The hypnotized foe is made to do Dusclops’s bidding.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="357" language="9" name="Tropius" genus="Fruit">Children of the southern tropics eat as snacks the fruit that
grows in bunches around the neck of Tropius. This Pokémon
flies by flapping the leaves on its back as if they were wings.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="358" language="9" name="Chimecho" genus="Wind Chime">In high winds, Chimecho cries as it hangs from a tree branch or
the eaves of a building using a suction cup on its head. This
Pokémon plucks berries with its long tail and eats them.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="359" language="9" name="Absol" genus="Disaster">Absol has the ability to foretell the coming of natural disasters.
It lives in a harsh, rugged mountain environment. This
Pokémon very rarely ventures down from the mountains.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="360" language="9" name="Wynaut" genus="Bright">Wynaut gather on moonlit nights to play by squeezing up
against each other. By being squeezed, this Pokémon gains
endurance and is trained to dole out powerful counterattacks.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="361" language="9" name="Snorunt" genus="Snow Hat">Snorunt survives by eating only snow and ice. Old folklore
claims that a house visited by this Pokémon is sure to prosper
for many generations to come.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="362" language="9" name="Glalie" genus="Face">Glalie has the ability to freely control ice. For example, it can
instantly freeze its prey solid. After immobilizing its prey in ice,
this Pokémon enjoys eating it in leisurely fashion.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="363" language="9" name="Spheal" genus="Clap">Spheal always travels by rolling around on its ball-like body.
When the season for ice floes arrives, this Pokémon can be
seen rolling about on ice and crossing the sea.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="364" language="9" name="Sealeo" genus="Ball Roll">Sealeo often balances and rolls things on the tip of its
nose. While the Pokémon is rolling something, it checks
the object’s aroma and texture to determine whether it likes
the object or not.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="365" language="9" name="Walrein" genus="Ice Break">Walrein swims all over in frigid seawater while crushing
icebergs with its grand, imposing tusks. Its thick layer of
blubber makes enemy attacks bounce off harmlessly.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="366" language="9" name="Clamperl" genus="Bivalve">Clamperl grows while being protected by its rock-hard shell.
When its body becomes too large to fit inside the shell, it is
sure evidence that this Pokémon is getting close to evolution.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="367" language="9" name="Huntail" genus="Deep Sea">Huntail’s tail is shaped like a fish. It uses the tail to attract
prey, then swallows the prey whole with its large, gaping
mouth. This Pokémon swims by wiggling its slender body
like a snake.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="368" language="9" name="Gorebyss" genus="South Sea">Although Gorebyss is the very picture of elegance and beauty
while swimming, it is also cruel. When it spots prey, this
Pokémon inserts its thin mouth into the prey’s body and drains
the prey of its body fluids.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="369" language="9" name="Relicanth" genus="Longevity">Relicanth is a rare species that was discovered in deep-sea
explorations. This Pokémon’s body withstands the enormous
water pressure of the ocean depths. Its body is covered in
tough scales that are like craggy rocks.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="370" language="9" name="Luvdisc" genus="Rendezvous">Luvdisc’s heart-shaped body is a symbol of love and romance.
It is said that any couple meeting this Pokémon is promised a
loving relationship that never ends.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="371" language="9" name="Bagon" genus="Rock Head">Bagon harbors a never-ending dream of one day soaring high
among the clouds. As if trying to dispel its frustration over its
inability to fly, this Pokémon slams its hard head against huge
rocks and shatters them into pebbles.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="372" language="9" name="Shelgon" genus="Endurance">Covering Shelgon’s body are outgrowths much like bones.
The shell is very hard and bounces off enemy attacks.
When awaiting evolution, this Pokémon hides away in a cavern.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="373" language="9" name="Salamence" genus="Dragon">By evolving into Salamence, this Pokémon finally
realizes its long-held dream of growing wings. To express
its joy, it flies and wheels all over the sky while spouting
flames from its mouth.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="374" language="9" name="Beldum" genus="Iron Ball">Beldum keeps itself floating by generating a magnetic force
that repels earth’s natural magnetism. When it sleeps, this
Pokémon anchors itself to a cliff using the hooks on its rear.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="375" language="9" name="Metang" genus="Iron Claw">When two Beldum fuse together, Metang is formed.
The brains of the Beldum are joined by a magnetic
nervous system. This Pokémon turns its arms to the
rear for traveling at high speed.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="376" language="9" name="Metagross" genus="Iron Leg">Metagross is the result of two Metang achieving fusion.
When hunting, this Pokémon pins the prey to the ground under
its massive body. It then eats the helpless victim using the
large mouth on its stomach.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="377" language="9" name="Regirock" genus="Rock Peak">Regirock’s body is composed entirely of rocks. Recently,
a study made the startling discovery that the rocks were all
unearthed from different locations.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="378" language="9" name="Regice" genus="Iceberg">Regice cloaks itself with frigid air of -328 degrees Fahrenheit.
Things will freeze solid just by going near this Pokémon.
Its icy body is so cold, it will not melt even if it is immersed
in magma.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="379" language="9" name="Registeel" genus="Iron">Registeel was imprisoned by people in ancient times.
The metal composing its body is thought to be a curious
substance that is not of this earth.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="380" language="9" name="Latias" genus="Eon">Latias is highly intelligent and capable of understanding
human speech. It is covered with a glass-like down.
The Pokémon enfolds its body with its down and refracts
light to alter its appearance.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="381" language="9" name="Latios" genus="Eon">Latios will only open its heart to a Trainer with a
compassionate spirit. This Pokémon can fly faster than a
jet plane by folding its forelegs to minimize air resistance.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="382" language="9" name="Kyogre" genus="Sea Basin">Kyogre is said to be the personification of the sea itself.
Legends tell of its many clashes against Groudon,
as each sought to gain the power of nature.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="383" language="9" name="Groudon" genus="Continent">Through Primal Reversion and with nature’s full power,
it will take back its true form. It can cause magma to
erupt and expand the landmass of the world.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="384" language="9" name="Rayquaza" genus="Sky High">It flies forever through the ozone layer, consuming
meteoroids for sustenance. The many meteoroids
in its body provide the energy it needs to Mega Evolve.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="385" language="9" name="Jirachi" genus="Wish">Jirachi will awaken from its sleep of a thousand years if you
sing to it in a voice of purity. It is said to make true any wish
that people desire.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="386" language="9" name="Deoxys" genus="DNA">Deoxys emerged from a virus that came from space. It is highly
intelligent and wields psychokinetic powers. This Pokémon
shoots lasers from the crystalline organ on its chest.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="387" language="9" name="Turtwig" genus="Tiny Leaf">It undertakes photosynthesis with its body, making
oxygen. The leaf on its head wilts if it is thirsty.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="388" language="9" name="Grotle" genus="Grove">It knows where pure water wells up. It carries fellow
Pokémon there on its back.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="389" language="9" name="Torterra" genus="Continent">Small Pokémon occasionally gather on its unmoving
back to begin building their nests.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="390" language="9" name="Chimchar" genus="Chimp">The gas made in its belly burns from its rear end.
The fire burns weakly when it feels sick.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="391" language="9" name="Monferno" genus="Playful">It uses ceilings and walls to launch aerial attacks.
Its fiery tail is but one weapon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="392" language="9" name="Infernape" genus="Flame">It tosses its enemies around with agility. It uses all
its limbs to fight in its own unique style.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="393" language="9" name="Piplup" genus="Penguin">Because it is very proud, it hates accepting food
from people. Its thick down guards it from cold.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="394" language="9" name="Prinplup" genus="Penguin">It lives a solitary life. Its wings deliver wicked blows
that can snap even the thickest of trees.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="395" language="9" name="Empoleon" genus="Emperor">The three horns that extend from its beak attest to
its power. The leader has the biggest horns.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="396" language="9" name="Starly" genus="Starling">They flock around mountains and fields, chasing
after bug Pokémon. Their singing is noisy
and annoying.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="397" language="9" name="Staravia" genus="Starling">It lives in forests and fields. Squabbles over
territory occur when flocks collide.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="398" language="9" name="Staraptor" genus="Predator">When Staravia evolve into Staraptor, they leave the
flock to live alone. They have sturdy wings.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="399" language="9" name="Bidoof" genus="Plump Mouse">It constantly gnaws on logs and rocks to whittle
down its front teeth. It nests alongside water.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="400" language="9" name="Bibarel" genus="Beaver">It makes its nest by damming streams with bark and
mud. It is known as an industrious worker.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="401" language="9" name="Kricketot" genus="Cricket">When its antennae hit each other, it sounds like the
music of a xylophone.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="402" language="9" name="Kricketune" genus="Cricket">It signals its emotions with its melodies. Scientists
are studying these melodic patterns.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="403" language="9" name="Shinx" genus="Flash">All of its fur dazzles if danger is sensed. It flees
while the foe is momentarily blinded.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="404" language="9" name="Luxio" genus="Spark">Strong electricity courses through the tips of its
sharp claws. A light scratch causes fainting in foes.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="405" language="9" name="Luxray" genus="Gleam Eyes">Luxray’s ability to see through objects comes in
handy when it’s scouting for danger.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="406" language="9" name="Budew" genus="Bud">Over the winter, it closes its bud and endures the
cold. In spring, the bud opens and releases pollen.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="407" language="9" name="Roserade" genus="Bouquet">With the movements of a dancer, it strikes with
whips that are densely lined with poison thorns.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="408" language="9" name="Cranidos" genus="Head Butt">A lifelong jungle dweller from 100 million years
ago, it would snap obstructing trees with headbutts.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="409" language="9" name="Rampardos" genus="Head Butt">Its skull is as hard as iron. It is a brute that tears
down jungle trees while catching prey.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="410" language="9" name="Shieldon" genus="Shield">It was generated from a fossil dug out of a layer of
clay that was older than anyone knows. It has a
sturdy face.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="411" language="9" name="Bastiodon" genus="Shield">Any frontal attack is repulsed. It is a docile
Pokémon that feeds on grass and berries.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="412" language="9" name="Burmy" genus="Bagworm">If its cloak is broken in battle, it quickly remakes
the cloak with materials nearby.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="413" language="9" name="Wormadam" genus="Bagworm">When Burmy evolved, its cloak became a part of
this Pokémon’s body. The cloak is never shed.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="414" language="9" name="Mothim" genus="Moth">It flutters around at night and steals honey from
the Combee hive.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="415" language="9" name="Combee" genus="Tiny Bee">It collects and delivers honey to its colony.
At night, they cluster to form a beehive and sleep.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="416" language="9" name="Vespiquen" genus="Beehive">Its abdomen is a honeycomb for grubs. It raises its
grubs on honey collected by Combee.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="417" language="9" name="Pachirisu" genus="EleSquirrel">A pair may be seen rubbing their cheek pouches
together in an effort to share stored electricity.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="418" language="9" name="Buizel" genus="Sea Weasel">It inflates the flotation sac around its neck and
pokes its head out of the water to see what is
going on.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="419" language="9" name="Floatzel" genus="Sea Weasel">Its flotation sac developed as a result of pursuing
aquatic prey. It can double as a rubber raft.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="420" language="9" name="Cherubi" genus="Cherry">It evolves by sucking the energy out of the small
ball where it had been storing nutrients.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="421" language="9" name="Cherrim" genus="Blossom">If it senses strong sunlight, it opens its folded
petals to absorb the sun’s rays with its whole body.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="422" language="9" name="Shellos" genus="Sea Slug">Its shape and coloration vary, depending on
its habitat.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="423" language="9" name="Gastrodon" genus="Sea Slug">It apparently had a huge shell for protection in
ancient times. It lives in shallow tidal pools.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="424" language="9" name="Ambipom" genus="Long Tail">To eat, it deftly shucks nuts with its two tails.
It rarely uses its arms now.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="425" language="9" name="Drifloon" genus="Balloon">These Pokémon are called the “Signpost for
Wandering Spirits.” Children holding them
sometimes vanish.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="426" language="9" name="Drifblim" genus="Blimp">It’s drowsy in daytime, but flies off in the evening in
big groups. No one knows where they go.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="427" language="9" name="Buneary" genus="Rabbit">When it senses danger, it perks up its ears.
On cold nights, it sleeps with its head tucked into
its fur.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="428" language="9" name="Lopunny" genus="Rabbit">The ears appear to be delicate. If they are touched
roughly, it kicks with its graceful legs.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="429" language="9" name="Mismagius" genus="Magical">Its cries sound like incantations to torment the foe.
It appears where you least expect it.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="430" language="9" name="Honchkrow" genus="Big Boss">Becoming active at night, it is known to swarm with
numerous Murkrow in tow.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="431" language="9" name="Glameow" genus="Catty">When it’s happy, Glameow demonstrates beautiful
movements of its tail, like a dancing ribbon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="432" language="9" name="Purugly" genus="Tiger Cat">To make itself appear intimidatingly beefy, it tightly
cinches its waist with its twin tails.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="433" language="9" name="Chingling" genus="Bell">There is an orb inside its mouth. When it hops,
the orb bounces all over and makes a
ringing sound.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="434" language="9" name="Stunky" genus="Skunk">It protects itself by spraying a noxious fluid from its
rear. The stench lingers for 24 hours.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="435" language="9" name="Skuntank" genus="Skunk">It sprays a stinky fluid from its tail. The fluid smells
worse the longer it is allowed to fester.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="436" language="9" name="Bronzor" genus="Bronze">Implements shaped like it were discovered in
ancient tombs. It is unknown if they are related.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="437" language="9" name="Bronzong" genus="Bronze Bell">Ancient people believed that petitioning Bronzong
for rain was the way to make crops grow.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="438" language="9" name="Bonsly" genus="Bonsai">It prefers an arid atmosphere. It leaks water that
looks like tears when adjusting its moisture level.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="439" language="9" name="Mime Jr." genus="Mime">It habitually mimics foes. Once mimicked, the foe
cannot take its eyes off this Pokémon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="440" language="9" name="Happiny" genus="Playhouse">It carefully carries a round, white rock that it thinks
is an egg. It’s bothered by how curly its hair looks.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="441" language="9" name="Chatot" genus="Music Note">It can learn and speak human words. If they gather,
they all learn the same saying.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="442" language="9" name="Spiritomb" genus="Forbidden">It was bound to a fissure in an odd keystone as
punishment for misdeeds 500 years ago.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="443" language="9" name="Gible" genus="Land Shark">It nests in small, horizontal holes in cave walls.
It pounces to catch prey that stray too close.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="444" language="9" name="Gabite" genus="Cave">As it digs to expand its nest, it habitually digs up
gems that it then hoards in its nest.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="445" language="9" name="Garchomp" genus="Mach">It flies at speeds equal to a jet fighter plane.
It never allows its prey to escape.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="446" language="9" name="Munchlax" genus="Big Eater">It conceals food under the long fur on its body.
It carts around this food stash and swallows it
without chewing.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="447" language="9" name="Riolu" genus="Emanation">The aura that emanates from its body intensifies to
alert others if it is afraid or sad.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="448" language="9" name="Lucario" genus="Aura">By reading the auras of all things, it can tell how
others are feeling from over half a mile away.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="449" language="9" name="Hippopotas" genus="Hippo">It enshrouds itself with sand to protect itself from
germs. It does not enjoy getting wet.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="450" language="9" name="Hippowdon" genus="Heavyweight">It blasts internally stored sand from ports on its
body to create a towering twister for attack.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="451" language="9" name="Skorupi" genus="Scorpion">It burrows under the sand to lie in wait for prey.
Its tail claws can inject its prey with a
savage poison.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="452" language="9" name="Drapion" genus="Ogre Scorpion">It has the power in its clawed arms to make scrap
of a car. The tips of its claws release poison.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="453" language="9" name="Croagunk" genus="Toxic Mouth">Inflating its poison sacs, it fills the area with an odd
sound and hits flinching opponents with a
poison jab.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="454" language="9" name="Toxicroak" genus="Toxic Mouth">Its knuckle claws secrete a toxin so vile that even a
scratch could prove fatal.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="455" language="9" name="Carnivine" genus="Bug Catcher">It binds itself to trees in marshes. It attracts prey
with its sweet-smelling drool and gulps them down.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="456" language="9" name="Finneon" genus="Wing Fish">After long exposure to sunlight, the patterns on its
tail fins shine vividly when darkness arrives.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="457" language="9" name="Lumineon" genus="Neon">To avoid detection by predators, it crawls along the
seafloor using the two fins on its chest.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="458" language="9" name="Mantyke" genus="Kite">When it swims close to the surface of the ocean,
people aboard ships are able to observe the pattern
on its back.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="459" language="9" name="Snover" genus="Frost Tree">In the spring, it grows berries with the texture of
frozen treats around its belly.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="460" language="9" name="Abomasnow" genus="Frost Tree">It lives a quiet life on mountains that are perpetually
covered in snow. It hides itself by whipping
up blizzards.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="461" language="9" name="Weavile" genus="Sharp Claw">They live in cold regions, forming groups of four or
five that hunt prey with impressive coordination.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="462" language="9" name="Magnezone" genus="Magnet Area">It evolved from exposure to a special magnetic
field. Three units generate magnetism.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="463" language="9" name="Lickilicky" genus="Licking">Their saliva contains lots of components that can
dissolve anything. The numbness caused by their
lick does not dissipate.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="464" language="9" name="Rhyperior" genus="Drill">It puts rocks in holes in its palms and uses its
muscles to shoot them. Geodude are shot at
rare times.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="465" language="9" name="Tangrowth" genus="Vine">Its vines grow so profusely that, in the warm
season, you can’t even see its eyes.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="466" language="9" name="Electivire" genus="Thunderbolt">It pushes the tips of its two tails against the foe,
then lets loose with over 20,000 volts of power.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="467" language="9" name="Magmortar" genus="Blast">It blasts fireballs of over 3,600 degrees Fahrenheit
out of its arms. Its breath also sears and sizzles.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="468" language="9" name="Togekiss" genus="Jubilee">It shares many blessings with people who respect
one another’s rights and avoid needless strife.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="469" language="9" name="Yanmega" genus="Ogre Darner">This six-legged Pokémon is easily capable of
transporting an adult in flight. The wings on its tail
help it stay balanced.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="470" language="9" name="Leafeon" genus="Verdant">Just like a plant, it uses photosynthesis. As a result,
it is always enveloped in clear air.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="471" language="9" name="Glaceon" genus="Fresh Snow">It lowers its body heat to freeze its fur. The hairs
then become like needles it can fire.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="472" language="9" name="Gliscor" genus="Fang Scorpion">Its flight is soundless. It uses its lengthy tail to
carry off its prey... Then its elongated fangs do
the rest.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="473" language="9" name="Mamoswine" genus="Twin Tusk">Its impressive tusks are made of ice. The population
thinned when it turned warm after the ice age.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="474" language="9" name="Porygon-Z" genus="Virtual">Its programming was modified to enable it to travel
through alien dimensions. Seems there might have
been an error...</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="475" language="9" name="Gallade" genus="Blade">A master of courtesy and swordsmanship, it fights
using extending swords on its elbows.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="476" language="9" name="Probopass" genus="Compass">It freely controls three small units called Mini-Noses
using magnetic force.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="477" language="9" name="Dusknoir" genus="Gripper">The antenna on its head captures radio waves from
the world of spirits that command it to take
people there.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="478" language="9" name="Froslass" genus="Snow Land">Legends in snowy regions say that a woman who
was lost on an icy mountain was reborn as Froslass.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="479" language="9" name="Rotom" genus="Plasma">Its body is composed of plasma. It is known to
infiltrate electronic devices and wreak havoc.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="480" language="9" name="Uxie" genus="Knowledge">It is said that its emergence gave humans the
intelligence to improve their quality of life.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="481" language="9" name="Mesprit" genus="Emotion">It sleeps at the bottom of a lake. Its spirit is said to
leave its body to fly on the lake’s surface.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="482" language="9" name="Azelf" genus="Willpower">It is thought that Uxie, Mesprit, and Azelf all came
from the same egg.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="483" language="9" name="Dialga" genus="Temporal">It has the power to control time. It appears in
Sinnoh-region myths as an ancient deity.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="484" language="9" name="Palkia" genus="Spatial">It has the ability to distort space. It is described as
a deity in Sinnoh-region mythology.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="485" language="9" name="Heatran" genus="Lava Dome">Boiling blood, like magma, circulates through its
body. It makes its dwelling place in volcanic caves.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="486" language="9" name="Regigigas" genus="Colossal">There is an enduring legend that states this
Pokémon towed continents with ropes.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="487" language="9" name="Giratina" genus="Renegade">It was banished for its violence. It silently gazed
upon the old world from the Distortion World.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="488" language="9" name="Cresselia" genus="Lunar">Those who sleep holding Cresselia’s feather are
assured of joyful dreams. It is said to represent
the crescent moon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="489" language="9" name="Phione" genus="Sea Drifter">It drifts in warm seas. It always returns to where it
was born, no matter how far it may have drifted.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="490" language="9" name="Manaphy" genus="Seafaring">It starts its life with a wondrous power that permits
it to bond with any kind of Pokémon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="491" language="9" name="Darkrai" genus="Pitch-Black">It can lull people to sleep and make them dream.
It is active during nights of the new moon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="492" language="9" name="Shaymin" genus="Gratitude">The blooming of Gracidea flowers confers the
power of flight upon it. Feelings of gratitude are
the message it delivers.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="493" language="9" name="Arceus" genus="Alpha">It is told in mythology that this Pokémon was born
before the universe even existed.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="494" language="9" name="Victini" genus="Victory">When it shares the infinite energy it creates,
that being’s entire body will be overflowing
with power.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="495" language="9" name="Snivy" genus="Grass Snake">They photosynthesize by bathing their tails in
sunlight. When they are not feeling well, their
tails droop.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="496" language="9" name="Servine" genus="Grass Snake">When it gets dirty, its leaves can’t be used in
photosynthesis, so it always keeps itself clean.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="497" language="9" name="Serperior" genus="Regal">It can stop its opponents’ movements with just a
glare. It takes in solar energy and boosts
it internally.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="498" language="9" name="Tepig" genus="Fire Pig">It loves to eat roasted berries, but sometimes it
gets too excited and burns them to a crisp.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="499" language="9" name="Pignite" genus="Fire Pig">When its internal fire flares up, its movements grow
sharper and faster. When in trouble, it emits smoke.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="500" language="9" name="Emboar" genus="Mega Fire Pig">It has mastered fast and powerful fighting moves.
It grows a beard of fire.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="501" language="9" name="Oshawott" genus="Sea Otter">It fights using the scalchop on its stomach.
In response to an attack, it retaliates immediately
by slashing.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="502" language="9" name="Dewott" genus="Discipline">As a result of strict training, each Dewott learns
different forms for using the scalchops.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="503" language="9" name="Samurott" genus="Formidable">One swing of the sword incorporated in its armor
can fell an opponent. A simple glare from one of
them quiets everybody.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="504" language="9" name="Patrat" genus="Scout">Extremely cautious, one of them will always be on
the lookout, but it won’t notice a foe coming
from behind.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="505" language="9" name="Watchog" genus="Lookout">When they see an enemy, their tails stand high,
and they spit the seeds of berries stored in their
cheek pouches.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="506" language="9" name="Lillipup" genus="Puppy">Though it is a very brave Pokémon, it’s also smart
enough to check its foe’s strength and avoid battle.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="507" language="9" name="Herdier" genus="Loyal Dog">It has black, cape-like fur that is very hard and
decreases the amount of damage it receives.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="508" language="9" name="Stoutland" genus="Big-Hearted">Being wrapped in its long fur is so comfortable
that a person would be fine even overnight on a
wintry mountain.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="509" language="9" name="Purrloin" genus="Devious">They steal from people for fun, but their victims
can’t help but forgive them. Their deceptively cute
act is perfect.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="510" language="9" name="Liepard" genus="Cruel">Stealthily, it sneaks up on its target, striking from
behind before its victim has a chance to react.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="511" language="9" name="Pansage" genus="Grass Monkey">It’s good at finding berries and gathers them from
all over. It’s kind enough to share them
with friends.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="512" language="9" name="Simisage" genus="Thorn Monkey">Ill tempered, it fights by swinging its barbed tail
around wildly. The leaf growing on its head is
very bitter.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="513" language="9" name="Pansear" genus="High Temp">This Pokémon lives in caves in volcanoes.
The fire within the tuft on its head can reach
600 degrees Fahrenheit.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="514" language="9" name="Simisear" genus="Ember">When it gets excited, embers rise from its head
and tail and it gets hot. For some reason, it
loves sweets.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="515" language="9" name="Panpour" genus="Spray">The water stored inside the tuft on its head is full of
nutrients. Plants that receive its water grow large.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="516" language="9" name="Simipour" genus="Geyser">It prefers places with clean water. When its tuft runs
low, it replenishes it by siphoning up water with
its tail.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="517" language="9" name="Munna" genus="Dream Eater">It eats the dreams of people and Pokémon. When it
eats a pleasant dream, it expels pink-colored mist.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="518" language="9" name="Musharna" genus="Drowsing">The dream mist coming from its forehead changes
into many different colors depending on the dream
that was eaten.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="519" language="9" name="Pidove" genus="Tiny Pigeon">These Pokémon live in cities. They are accustomed
to people. Flocks often gather in parks and plazas.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="520" language="9" name="Tranquill" genus="Wild Pigeon">No matter where in the world it goes, it knows
where its nest is, so it never gets separated from
its Trainer.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="521" language="9" name="Unfezant" genus="Proud">Males have plumage on their heads. They will never
let themselves feel close to anyone other than
their Trainers.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="522" language="9" name="Blitzle" genus="Electrified">Its mane shines when it discharges electricity.
They use the frequency and rhythm of these flashes
to communicate.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="523" language="9" name="Zebstrika" genus="Thunderbolt">They have lightning-like movements.
When Zebstrika run at full speed, the sound of
thunder reverberates.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="524" language="9" name="Roggenrola" genus="Mantle">They were discovered a hundred years ago in an
earthquake fissure. Inside each one is an
energy core.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="525" language="9" name="Boldore" genus="Ore">When it is healthy, its core sticks out. Always facing
the same way, it swiftly moves front to back and left
to right.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="526" language="9" name="Gigalith" genus="Compressed">Compressing the energy from its internal core
lets it fire off an attack capable of blowing away
a mountain.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="527" language="9" name="Woobat" genus="Bat">The heart-shaped mark left on a body after a
Woobat has been attached to it is said to bring
good fortune.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="528" language="9" name="Swoobat" genus="Courting">Anyone who comes into contact with the ultrasonic
waves emitted by a courting male experiences a
positive mood shift.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="529" language="9" name="Drilbur" genus="Mole">By spinning its body, it can dig straight through the
ground at a speed of 30 mph.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="530" language="9" name="Excadrill" genus="Subterrene">More than 300 feet below the surface, they build
mazelike nests. Their activity can be destructive to
subway tunnels.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="531" language="9" name="Audino" genus="Hearing">It touches others with the feelers on its ears, using
the sound of their heartbeats to tell how they
are feeling.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="532" language="9" name="Timburr" genus="Muscular">Always carrying squared logs, they help out with
construction. As they grow, they carry bigger logs.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="533" language="9" name="Gurdurr" genus="Muscular">This Pokémon is so muscular and strongly built that
even a group of wrestlers could not make it budge
an inch.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="534" language="9" name="Conkeldurr" genus="Muscular">Rather than rely on force, they master moves that
utilize the centrifugal force of spinning concrete.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="535" language="9" name="Tympole" genus="Tadpole">By vibrating its cheeks, it emits sound waves
imperceptible to humans. It uses the rhythm of
these sounds to talk.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="536" language="9" name="Palpitoad" genus="Vibration">It lives in the water and on land. It uses its long,
sticky tongue to immobilize its opponents.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="537" language="9" name="Seismitoad" genus="Vibration">They shoot paralyzing liquid from their head bumps.
They use vibration to hurt their opponents.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="538" language="9" name="Throh" genus="Judo">When it encounters a foe bigger than itself, it wants
to throw it. It changes belts as it gets stronger.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="539" language="9" name="Sawk" genus="Karate">Tying their belts gets them pumped and makes their
punches more destructive. Disturbing their training
angers them.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="540" language="9" name="Sewaddle" genus="Sewing">Since this Pokémon makes its own clothes out of
leaves, it is a popular mascot for fashion designers.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="541" language="9" name="Swadloon" genus="Leaf-Wrapped">It protects itself from the cold by wrapping up in
leaves. It stays on the move, eating leaves
in forests.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="542" language="9" name="Leavanny" genus="Nurturing">It keeps its eggs warm with heat from fermenting
leaves. It also uses leaves to make warm wrappings
for Sewaddle.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="543" language="9" name="Venipede" genus="Centipede">Its bite injects a potent poison, enough to paralyze
large bird Pokémon that try to prey on it.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="544" language="9" name="Whirlipede" genus="Curlipede">It is usually motionless, but when attacked,
it rotates at high speed and then crashes into
its opponent.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="545" language="9" name="Scolipede" genus="Megapede">With quick movements, it chases down its foes,
attacking relentlessly with its horns until it prevails.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="546" language="9" name="Cottonee" genus="Cotton Puff">Perhaps because they feel more at ease in a group,
they stick to others they find. They end up looking
like a cloud.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="547" language="9" name="Whimsicott" genus="Windveiled">Like the wind, it can slip through any gap,
no matter how small. It leaves balls of white
fluff behind.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="548" language="9" name="Petilil" genus="Bulb">Since they prefer moist, nutrient-rich soil, the areas
where Petilil live are known to be good for
growing plants.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="549" language="9" name="Lilligant" genus="Flowering">Even veteran Trainers face a challenge in getting its
beautiful flower to bloom. This Pokémon is popular
with celebrities.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="550" language="9" name="Basculin" genus="Hostile">Red and blue Basculin usually do not get along,
but sometimes members of one school mingle with
the other’s school.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="551" language="9" name="Sandile" genus="Desert Croc">They live buried in the sands of the desert.
The sun-warmed sands prevent their body
temperature from dropping.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="552" language="9" name="Krokorok" genus="Desert Croc">The special membrane covering its eyes can sense
the heat of objects, so it can see its surroundings
even in darkness.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="553" language="9" name="Krookodile" genus="Intimidation">They never allow prey to escape. Their jaws
are so powerful, they can crush the body of
an automobile.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="554" language="9" name="Darumaka" genus="Zen Charm">When it sleeps, it pulls its limbs into its
body and its internal fire goes down to
1,100 degrees Fahrenheit.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="555" language="9" name="Darmanitan" genus="Blazing">Its internal fire burns at 2,500 degrees Fahrenheit,
making enough power that it can destroy a dump
truck with one punch.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="556" language="9" name="Maractus" genus="Cactus">Arid regions are their habitat. They move
rhythmically, making a sound similar to maracas.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="557" language="9" name="Dwebble" genus="Rock Inn">When it finds a stone of a suitable size, it secretes
a liquid from its mouth to open up a hole to
crawl into.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="558" language="9" name="Crustle" genus="Stone Home">Competing for territory, Crustle fight viciously.
The one whose boulder is broken is the loser of
the battle.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="559" language="9" name="Scraggy" genus="Shedding">Proud of its sturdy skull, it suddenly headbutts
everything, but its weight makes it unstable, too.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="560" language="9" name="Scrafty" genus="Hoodlum">It can smash concrete blocks with its kicking
attacks. The one with the biggest crest is the
group leader.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="561" language="9" name="Sigilyph" genus="Avianoid">The guardians of an ancient city, they always fly
the same route while keeping watch for invaders.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="562" language="9" name="Yamask" genus="Spirit">Each of them carries a mask that used to be its face
when it was human. Sometimes they look at it
and cry.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="563" language="9" name="Cofagrigus" genus="Coffin">Grave robbers who mistake them for real coffins and
get too close end up trapped inside their bodies.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="564" language="9" name="Tirtouga" genus="Prototurtle">Restored from a fossil, this Pokémon can dive to
depths beyond half a mile.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="565" language="9" name="Carracosta" genus="Prototurtle">It could knock out a foe with a slap from one of its
developed front appendages and chew it up, shell
or bones and all.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="566" language="9" name="Archen" genus="First Bird">Said to be an ancestor of bird Pokémon, they were
unable to fly and moved about by hopping from one
branch to another.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="567" language="9" name="Archeops" genus="First Bird">It runs better than it flies. It takes off into the sky
by running at a speed of 25 mph.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="568" language="9" name="Trubbish" genus="Trash Bag">Inhaling the gas they belch will make you sleep for
a week. They prefer unsanitary places.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="569" language="9" name="Garbodor" genus="Trash Heap">Consuming garbage makes new kinds of poison
gases and liquids inside their bodies.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="570" language="9" name="Zorua" genus="Tricky Fox">To protect themselves from danger, they hide their
true identities by transforming into people
and Pokémon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="571" language="9" name="Zoroark" genus="Illusion Fox">Bonds between these Pokémon are very strong.
It protects the safety of its pack by tricking
its opponents.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="572" language="9" name="Minccino" genus="Chinchilla">These Pokémon prefer a tidy habitat. They are
always sweeping and dusting, using their tails
as brooms.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="573" language="9" name="Cinccino" genus="Scarf">Cinccino’s body is coated in a special oil that helps
it deflect attacks, such as punches.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="574" language="9" name="Gothita" genus="Fixation">They intently observe both Trainers and Pokémon.
Apparently, they are looking at something that only
Gothita can see.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="575" language="9" name="Gothorita" genus="Manipulate">According to many old tales, it creates friends for
itself by controlling sleeping children on
starry nights.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="576" language="9" name="Gothitelle" genus="Astral Body">They can predict the future from the placement and
movement of the stars. They can see Trainers’
life spans.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="577" language="9" name="Solosis" genus="Cell">They drive away attackers by unleashing psychic
power. They can use telepathy to talk with others.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="578" language="9" name="Duosion" genus="Mitosis">When their two divided brains think the same
thoughts, their psychic power is maximized.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="579" language="9" name="Reuniclus" genus="Multiplying">When Reuniclus shake hands, a network forms
between their brains, increasing their
psychic power.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="580" language="9" name="Ducklett" genus="Water Bird">They are better at swimming than flying, and they
happily eat their favorite food, peat moss, as they
dive underwater.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="581" language="9" name="Swanna" genus="White Bird">Swanna start to dance at dusk. The one dancing in
the middle is the leader of the flock.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="582" language="9" name="Vanillite" genus="Fresh Snow">This Pokémon formed from icicles bathed in energy
from the morning sun. It sleeps buried in snow.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="583" language="9" name="Vanillish" genus="Icy Snow">Snowy mountains are this Pokémon’s habitat.
During an ancient ice age, they moved to
southern areas.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="584" language="9" name="Vanilluxe" genus="Snowstorm">Swallowing large amounts of water, they make
snow clouds inside their bodies and, when angry,
cause violent blizzards.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="585" language="9" name="Deerling" genus="Season">The turning of the seasons changes the color and
scent of this Pokémon’s fur. People use it to mark
the seasons.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="586" language="9" name="Sawsbuck" genus="Season">They migrate according to the seasons, so some
people call Sawsbuck the harbingers of spring.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="587" language="9" name="Emolga" genus="Sky Squirrel">The energy made in its cheeks’ electric pouches is
stored inside its membrane and released while it
is gliding.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="588" language="9" name="Karrablast" genus="Clamping">For some reason they evolve when they receive
electrical energy while they are attacking Shelmet.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="589" language="9" name="Escavalier" genus="Cavalry">These Pokémon evolve by wearing the shell
covering of a Shelmet. The steel armor protects
their whole body.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="590" language="9" name="Foongus" genus="Mushroom">It lures Pokémon with its pattern that looks just like
a Poké Ball, then releases poison spores.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="591" language="9" name="Amoonguss" genus="Mushroom">It lures prey close by dancing and waving its
arm caps, which resemble Poké Balls, in a
swaying motion.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="592" language="9" name="Frillish" genus="Floating">If its veil-like arms stun and wrap a foe, that foe will
be dragged miles below the surface, never
to return.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="593" language="9" name="Jellicent" genus="Floating">The fate of the ships and crew that wander into
Jellicent’s habitat: all sunken, all lost, all vanished.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="594" language="9" name="Alomomola" genus="Caring">It gently holds injured and weak Pokémon in its
fins. Its special membrane heals their wounds.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="595" language="9" name="Joltik" genus="Attaching">They attach themselves to large-bodied Pokémon
and absorb static electricity, which they store in an
electric pouch.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="596" language="9" name="Galvantula" genus="EleSpider">When attacked, they create an electric barrier by
spitting out many electrically charged threads.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="597" language="9" name="Ferroseed" genus="Thorn Seed">It absorbs the iron it finds in the rock while clinging
to the ceiling. It shoots spikes when in danger.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="598" language="9" name="Ferrothorn" genus="Thorn Pod">They attach themselves to cave ceilings, firing steel
spikes at targets passing beneath them.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="599" language="9" name="Klink" genus="Gear">The two minigears that mesh together are
predetermined. Each will rebound from other
minigears without meshing.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="600" language="9" name="Klang" genus="Gear">A minigear and big gear comprise its body. If the
minigear it launches at a foe doesn’t return, it
will die.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="601" language="9" name="Klinklang" genus="Gear">Its red core functions as an energy tank. It fires the
charged energy through its spikes into an area.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="602" language="9" name="Tynamo" genus="EleFish">One alone can emit only a trickle of electricity,
so a group of them gathers to unleash a powerful
electric shock.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="603" language="9" name="Eelektrik" genus="EleFish">These Pokémon have a big appetite. When they
spot their prey, they attack it and paralyze it
with electricity.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="604" language="9" name="Eelektross" genus="EleFish">They crawl out of the ocean using their arms.
They will attack prey on shore and immediately drag
it into the ocean.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="605" language="9" name="Elgyem" genus="Cerebral">Rumors of its origin are linked to a UFO crash site
in the desert 50 years ago.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="606" language="9" name="Beheeyem" genus="Cerebral">It uses psychic power to control an opponent’s
brain and tamper with its memories.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="607" language="9" name="Litwick" genus="Candle">Litwick shines a light that absorbs the life energy of
people and Pokémon, which becomes the fuel that
it burns.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="608" language="9" name="Lampent" genus="Lamp">It arrives near the moment of death and steals spirit
from the body.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="609" language="9" name="Chandelure" genus="Luring">The spirits burned up in its ominous flame lose their
way and wander this world forever.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="610" language="9" name="Axew" genus="Tusk">They mark their territory by leaving gashes in trees
with their tusks. If a tusk breaks, a new one grows
in quickly.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="611" language="9" name="Fraxure" genus="Axe Jaw">A broken tusk will not grow back, so it diligently
sharpens its tusks on river rocks after the end of
a battle.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="612" language="9" name="Haxorus" genus="Axe Jaw">Their sturdy tusks will stay sharp even if used to cut
steel beams. These Pokémon are covered in
hard armor.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="613" language="9" name="Cubchoo" genus="Chill">Their snot is a barometer of health. When healthy,
their snot is sticky and the power of their ice
moves increases.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="614" language="9" name="Beartic" genus="Freezing">It freezes its breath to create fangs and claws of ice
to fight with. Cold northern areas are its habitat.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="615" language="9" name="Cryogonal" genus="Crystallizing">They are composed of ice crystals. They capture
prey with chains of ice, freezing the prey at
-148 degrees Fahrenheit.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="616" language="9" name="Shelmet" genus="Snail">It evolves when bathed in an electric-like energy
along with Karrablast. The reason is still unknown.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="617" language="9" name="Accelgor" genus="Shell Out">When its body dries out, it weakens. So, to prevent
dehydration, it wraps itself in many layers of
thin membrane.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="618" language="9" name="Stunfisk" genus="Trap">It conceals itself in the mud of the seashore.
Then it waits. When prey touch it, it delivers a jolt
of electricity.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="619" language="9" name="Mienfoo" genus="Martial Arts">In fights, they dominate with onslaughts of flowing,
continuous attacks. With their sharp claws, they
cut enemies.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="620" language="9" name="Mienshao" genus="Martial Arts">Using the long fur on its arms like whips, it
launches into combo attacks that, once started,
no one can stop.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="621" language="9" name="Druddigon" genus="Cave">It warms its body by absorbing sunlight with its
wings. When its body temperature falls, it can no
longer move.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="622" language="9" name="Golett" genus="Automaton">Ancient science fashioned this Pokémon from clay.
It’s been active for thousands of years.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="623" language="9" name="Golurk" genus="Automaton">It flies across the sky at Mach speeds. Removing
the seal on its chest makes its internal energy go
out of control.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="624" language="9" name="Pawniard" genus="Sharp Blade">Ignoring their injuries, groups attack by sinking
the blades that cover their bodies into their prey.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="625" language="9" name="Bisharp" genus="Sword Blade">Bisharp pursues prey in the company of a large
group of Pawniard. Then Bisharp finishes off
the prey.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="626" language="9" name="Bouffalant" genus="Bash Buffalo">Their fluffy fur absorbs damage, even if they strike
foes with a fierce headbutt.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="627" language="9" name="Rufflet" genus="Eaglet">They will challenge anything, even strong
opponents, without fear. Their frequent fights help
them become stronger.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="628" language="9" name="Braviary" genus="Valiant">They fight for their friends without any thought
about danger to themselves. One can carry a car
while flying.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="629" language="9" name="Vullaby" genus="Diapered">Their wings are too tiny to allow them to fly.
They guard their posteriors with bones that were
gathered by Mandibuzz.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="630" language="9" name="Mandibuzz" genus="Bone Vulture">Watching from the sky, they swoop to strike
weakened Pokémon on the ground. They decorate
themselves with bones.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="631" language="9" name="Heatmor" genus="Anteater">It draws in air through its tail, transforms it into fire,
and uses it like a tongue. It melts Durant and
eats them.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="632" language="9" name="Durant" genus="Iron Ant">They attack in groups, covering themselves in steel
armor to protect themselves from Heatmor.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="633" language="9" name="Deino" genus="Irate">Lacking sight, it’s unaware of its surroundings,
so it bumps into things and eats anything
that moves.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="634" language="9" name="Zweilous" genus="Hostile">After it has eaten up all the food in its territory,
it moves to another area. Its two heads do not
get along.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="635" language="9" name="Hydreigon" genus="Brutal">It responds to movement by attacking. This scary,
three-headed Pokémon devours everything in
its path!</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="636" language="9" name="Larvesta" genus="Torch">The base of volcanoes is where they make their
homes. They shoot fire from their five horns to repel
attacking enemies.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="637" language="9" name="Volcarona" genus="Sun">When volcanic ash darkened the atmosphere, it is
said that Volcarona’s fire provided a replacement
for the sun.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="638" language="9" name="Cobalion" genus="Iron Will">It has a body and heart of steel. It worked with its
allies to punish people when they hurt Pokémon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="639" language="9" name="Terrakion" genus="Cavern">Spoken of in legend, this Pokémon used its
phenomenal power to destroy a castle in its effort
to protect Pokémon.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="640" language="9" name="Virizion" genus="Grassland">Legends say this Pokémon confounded opponents
with its swift movements.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="641" language="9" name="Tornadus" genus="Cyclone">Tornadus expels massive energy from its tail,
causing severe storms. Its power is great enough
to blow houses away.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="642" language="9" name="Thundurus" genus="Bolt Strike">As it flies around, it shoots lightning all over
the place and causes forest fires. It is
therefore disliked.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="643" language="9" name="Reshiram" genus="Vast White">When Reshiram’s tail flares, the heat energy moves
the atmosphere and changes the world’s weather.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="644" language="9" name="Zekrom" genus="Deep Black">Concealing itself in lightning clouds, it flies
throughout the Unova region. It creates electricity
in its tail.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="645" language="9" name="Landorus" genus="Abundance">From the forces of lightning and wind, it creates
energy to give nutrients to the soil and make the
land abundant.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="646" language="9" name="Kyurem" genus="Boundary">It generates a powerful, freezing energy inside
itself, but its body became frozen when the energy
leaked out.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="647" language="9" name="Keldeo" genus="Colt">When it is resolute, its body fills with power and it
becomes swifter. Its jumps are then too fast
to follow.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="648" language="9" name="Meloetta" genus="Melody">Its melodies are sung with a special vocalization
method that can control the feelings of those who
hear it.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="649" language="9" name="Genesect" genus="Paleozoic">This Pokémon existed 300 million years ago. Team
Plasma altered it and attached a cannon to its back.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="650" language="9" name="Chespin" genus="Spiny Nut">Such a thick shell of wood covers its head and back
that even a direct hit from a truck wouldn’t faze it.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="651" language="9" name="Quilladin" genus="Spiny Armor">They strengthen their lower bodies by
running into one another. They are very
kind and won’t start fights.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="652" language="9" name="Chesnaught" genus="Spiny Armor">When it takes a defensive posture with its fists
guarding its face, it could withstand a bomb blast.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="653" language="9" name="Fennekin" genus="Fox">As it walks, it munches on a twig in place
of a snack. It intimidates opponents
by puffing hot air out of its ears.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="654" language="9" name="Braixen" genus="Fox">When the twig is plucked from its tail,
friction sets the twig alight. The flame
is used to send signals to its allies.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="655" language="9" name="Delphox" genus="Fox">Using psychic power, it generates a
fiery vortex of 5,400 degrees Fahrenheit,
incinerating foes swept into this whirl of flame.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="656" language="9" name="Froakie" genus="Bubble Frog">It protects its skin by covering its body in
delicate bubbles. Beneath its happy-go-lucky air,
it keeps a watchful eye on its surroundings.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="657" language="9" name="Frogadier" genus="Bubble Frog">Its swiftness is unparalleled.
It can scale a tower of more
than 2,000 feet in a minute’s time.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="658" language="9" name="Greninja" genus="Ninja">It appears and vanishes with a ninja’s grace.
It toys with its enemies using swift movements, while
slicing them with throwing stars of sharpest water.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="659" language="9" name="Bunnelby" genus="Digging">It has ears like shovels. Digging holes
strengthens its ears so much that they
can sever thick roots effortlessly.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="660" language="9" name="Diggersby" genus="Digging">As powerful as an excavator, its ears
can reduce dense bedrock to rubble.
When it’s finished digging, it lounges lazily.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="661" language="9" name="Fletchling" genus="Tiny Robin">Despite the beauty of its lilting voice, it’s
merciless to intruders that enter its territory.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="662" language="9" name="Fletchinder" genus="Ember">The hotter the flame sac on its belly,
the faster it can fly, but it takes some
time to get the fire going.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="663" language="9" name="Talonflame" genus="Scorching">When attacking prey, it can reach speeds
of up to 310 mph. It finishes its prey off
with a colossal kick.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="664" language="9" name="Scatterbug" genus="Scatterdust">The powder that covers its body
regulates its temperature, so it
can live in any region or climate.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="665" language="9" name="Spewpa" genus="Scatterdust">The beaks of bird Pokémon can’t begin
to scratch its stalwart body.
To defend itself, it spews powder.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="666" language="9" name="Vivillon" genus="Scale">The patterns on this Pokémon’s wings
depend on the climate and topography
of its habitat. It scatters colorful scales.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="667" language="9" name="Litleo" genus="Lion Cub">They set off on their own from their pride
and live by themselves to become stronger.
These hot-blooded Pokémon are quick to fight.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="668" language="9" name="Pyroar" genus="Royal">With fiery breath of more than 10,000 degrees
Fahrenheit, they viciously threaten any challenger.
The females protect the pride’s cubs.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="669" language="9" name="Flabébé" genus="Single Bloom">When it finds a flower it likes, it dwells on
that flower its whole life long. It floats in the
wind’s embrace with an untroubled heart.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="670" language="9" name="Floette" genus="Single Bloom">When the flowers of a well-tended flower bed bloom,
it appears and celebrates with an elegant dance.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="671" language="9" name="Florges" genus="Garden">In times long past, governors of castles
would invite Florges to create flower gardens
to embellish the castle domains.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="672" language="9" name="Skiddo" genus="Mount">If it has sunshine and water, it doesn’t
need to eat, because it can generate
energy from the leaves on its back.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="673" language="9" name="Gogoat" genus="Mount">They inhabit mountainous regions.
The leader of the herd is decided by
a battle of clashing horns.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="674" language="9" name="Pancham" genus="Playful">It does its level best to glare and pull a scary face,
but it can’t help grinning if anyone pats its head.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="675" language="9" name="Pangoro" genus="Daunting">It charges ahead and bashes its opponents like
a berserker, uncaring about any hits it might take.
Its arms are mighty enough to snap a telephone pole.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="676" language="9" name="Furfrou" genus="Poodle">Historically, in the Kalos region, these Pokémon
were the designated guardians of the king.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="677" language="9" name="Espurr" genus="Restraint">It has enough psychic energy to blast
everything within 300 feet of itself,
but it has no control over its power.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="678" language="9" name="Meowstic" genus="Constraint">The eyeball patterns on the interior of its ears
emit psychic energy. It keeps the patterns tightly
covered because that power is too immense.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="679" language="9" name="Honedge" genus="Sword">If anyone dares to grab its hilt, it wraps
a blue cloth around that person’s arm and
drains that person’s life energy completely.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="680" language="9" name="Doublade" genus="Sword">The complex attack patterns of its two swords
are unstoppable, even for an opponent
greatly accomplished at swordplay.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="681" language="9" name="Aegislash" genus="Royal Sword">Apparently, it can detect the innate qualities
of leadership. According to legend, whoever it
recognizes is destined to become king.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="682" language="9" name="Spritzee" genus="Perfume">In the past, rather than using perfume,
royal ladies carried a Spritzee
that would waft a fragrance they liked.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="683" language="9" name="Aromatisse" genus="Fragrance">Its scent is so overpowering that, unless a Trainer
happens to really enjoy the smell, he or she will
have a hard time walking alongside it.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="684" language="9" name="Swirlix" genus="Cotton Candy">Because it eats nothing but sweets,
its fur is as sticky sweet as cotton candy.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="685" language="9" name="Slurpuff" genus="Meringue">Its sense of smell is 100 million times better than
a human’s, so even the faintest scent tells it about
everything in the area. It’s like it can see with its nose!</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="686" language="9" name="Inkay" genus="Revolving">It flashes the light-emitting spots on its body,
which drains its opponent’s will to fight.
It takes the opportunity to scuttle away and hide.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="687" language="9" name="Malamar" genus="Overturning">It lures its prey close with hypnotic motions,
then wraps its tentacles around it before
finishing it off with digestive fluids.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="688" language="9" name="Binacle" genus="Two-Handed">They stretch and then contract, yanking their
rocks along with them in bold hops. They eat
seaweed that washes up on the shoreline.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="689" language="9" name="Barbaracle" genus="Collective">Barbaracle’s legs and hands have minds
of their own, and they will move independently.
But they usually follow the head’s orders.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="690" language="9" name="Skrelp" genus="Mock Kelp">It looks just like rotten kelp. It hides from foes
while storing up power for its evolution.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="691" language="9" name="Dragalge" genus="Mock Kelp">Tales are told of ships that wander into
seas where Dragalge live, never to return.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="692" language="9" name="Clauncher" genus="Water Gun">Through controlled explosions of internal gas,
it can expel water like a pistol shot.
At close distances, it can shatter rock.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="693" language="9" name="Clawitzer" genus="Howitzer">By expelling water from the nozzle in the back
of its claw, it can move at a speed of 60 knots.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="694" language="9" name="Helioptile" genus="Generator">The frills on either side of its head have cells
that generate electricity when exposed to sunlight.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="695" language="9" name="Heliolisk" genus="Generator">It stimulates its muscles with electricity,
boosting the strength in its legs and enabling
it to run 100 yards in five seconds.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="696" language="9" name="Tyrunt" genus="Royal Heir">Its immense jaws have enough destructive
force that it can chew up an automobile.
It lived 100 million years ago.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="697" language="9" name="Tyrantrum" genus="Despot">Nothing could stop this Pokémon
100 million years ago,
so it behaved like a king.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="698" language="9" name="Amaura" genus="Tundra">This calm Pokémon lived in a cold land where
there were no violent predators like Tyrantrum.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="699" language="9" name="Aurorus" genus="Tundra">Using its diamond-shaped crystals,
it can instantly create a wall of
ice to block an opponent’s attack.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="700" language="9" name="Sylveon" genus="Intertwining">It wraps its ribbonlike feelers around
the arm of its beloved Trainer
and walks with him or her.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="701" language="9" name="Hawlucha" genus="Wrestling">With its wings, it controls its position in the air.
It likes to attack from above, a maneuver that
is difficult to defend against.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="702" language="9" name="Dedenne" genus="Antenna">It uses its tail to absorb electricity from
power plants or from outlets in houses,
and then it fires the electricity from its whiskers.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="703" language="9" name="Carbink" genus="Jewel">It has slept underground for hundreds of millions
of years since its birth. It’s occasionally found
during the excavation of caves.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="704" language="9" name="Goomy" genus="Soft Tissue">It’s covered in a slimy membrane that makes
any punches or kicks slide off it harmlessly.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="705" language="9" name="Sliggoo" genus="Soft Tissue">Its four horns are a high-performance radar system.
It uses them to sense sounds and smells,
rather than using ears or a nose.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="706" language="9" name="Goodra" genus="Dragon">It attacks with retractable horns.
It throws a punch that’s the equivalent
of the force of a hundred pro boxers.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="707" language="9" name="Klefki" genus="Key Ring">It never lets go of a key that it likes,
so people give it the keys to vaults and
safes as a way to prevent crime.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="708" language="9" name="Phantump" genus="Stump">According to old tales, these Pokémon are
stumps possessed by the spirits of
children who died while lost in the forest.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="709" language="9" name="Trevenant" genus="Elder Tree">Using its roots as a nervous system,
it controls the trees in the forest.
It’s kind to the Pokémon that reside in its body.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="710" language="9" name="Pumpkaboo" genus="Pumpkin">It is said to carry wandering spirits
to the place where they belong
so they can move on.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="711" language="9" name="Gourgeist" genus="Pumpkin">It enwraps its prey in its hairlike arms.
It sings joyfully as it observes the
suffering of its prey.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="712" language="9" name="Bergmite" genus="Ice Chunk">Using air of -150 degrees Fahrenheit, they
freeze opponents solid. They live in herds
above the snow line on mountains.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="713" language="9" name="Avalugg" genus="Iceberg">The way several Bergmite huddle
on its back makes it look like
an aircraft carrier made of ice.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="714" language="9" name="Noibat" genus="Sound Wave">Even a robust wrestler will become
dizzy and unable to stand when exposed
to its 200,000-hertz ultrasonic waves.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="715" language="9" name="Noivern" genus="Sound Wave">The ultrasonic waves it emits from its ears
can reduce a large boulder to pebbles.
It swoops out of the dark to attack.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="716" language="9" name="Xerneas" genus="Life">When the horns on its head shine
in seven colors, it is said to be
sharing everlasting life.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="717" language="9" name="Yveltal" genus="Destruction">When its life comes to an end, it absorbs
the life energy of every living thing
and turns into a cocoon once more.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="718" language="9" name="Zygarde" genus="Order">It’s hypothesized that it’s monitoring
those who destroy the ecosystem
from deep in the cave where it lives.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="719" language="9" name="Diancie" genus="Jewel">It can instantly create many diamonds
by compressing the carbon in the air
between its hands.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="720" language="9" name="Hoopa" genus="Mischief">It is said to be able to seize anything it desires
with its six rings and six huge arms. With its power
sealed, it is transformed into a much smaller form.</Pokemon>
<Pokemon id="721" language="9" name="Volcanion" genus="Steam">It expels its internal steam from the
arms on its back. It has enough
power to blow away a mountain.</Pokemon>
  </Species>
</Language>